<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The city of London's plea to the Quo warranto, (an information) brought against their Charter in Michaelmas term, 1681 wherein it will appear, that the liberties, priviledges, and customs of the said city cannot be forfeited, or lost by the misdemeanor of any officer or magistrate thereof, nor their Charter be seized into the King's hands for any mis-usage or abusage of their liberties and priviledges, they being confirmed by divers ancient records and acts of Parliament made before and since Magna Charta : also, how far the Commons of the said city have power of chusing and removing their sheriffs / published both in English and Latin.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1682</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 126 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 19 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2013-12">2013-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A33193</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing C4360</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R15339</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">12950761</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 12950761</idno>
            <idno type="VID">95897</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A33193)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 95897)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 733:40)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The city of London's plea to the Quo warranto, (an information) brought against their Charter in Michaelmas term, 1681 wherein it will appear, that the liberties, priviledges, and customs of the said city cannot be forfeited, or lost by the misdemeanor of any officer or magistrate thereof, nor their Charter be seized into the King's hands for any mis-usage or abusage of their liberties and priviledges, they being confirmed by divers ancient records and acts of Parliament made before and since Magna Charta : also, how far the Commons of the said city have power of chusing and removing their sheriffs / published both in English and Latin.</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[2], 31 [i.e. 35] p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed and published by Randal Taylor,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1682.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Errors in paging.</note>
                  <note>Latin and English in parallel columns.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in Huntington Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>London (England). --  Charter.</term>
               <term>City of London (England). --  Court of Common Council.</term>
               <term>London (England) --  Charters, grants, privileges.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2012-06</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-06</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-01</date>
            <label>Colm MacCrossan</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-01</date>
            <label>Colm MacCrossan</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-02</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:95897:1"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:95897:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p>THE City of London's PLEA TO THE Quo Warranto, (An Information) brought againſt their CHARTER In <hi>Michaelmas</hi> Term, 1681. <hi>WHEREIN</hi> It will Appear, That the Liberties, Priviledges, and Cuſtoms of the ſaid City cannot be Forfeited, or Loſt by the Miſdemeanor of any Officer or Magiſtrate thereof. Nor their CHARTER be Seized into the King's Hands for any Miſ-uſage or Abu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſage of their Liberties and Priviledges, they being Confirmed by divers Ancient Records and Acts of Parliament made be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore and ſince <hi>MAGNA CHARTA.</hi> ALSO, How far the Commons of the ſaid City have Power of Chuſing and Removing their SHERIFFS. <hi>Publiſhed Both in Engliſh and Latin.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>London,</hi> Printed in the Year 1682. And Publiſhed by <hi>Randal Taylor.</hi>
            </p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="legal_document">
            <div xml:lang="lat" type="version">
               <pb facs="tcp:95897:2"/>
               <pb n="1" facs="tcp:95897:2"/>
               <head>Per Informat' Mich. xxxiii Car. Secund. Reg.</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>Lond. ſſ.</hi> MEmorandum quod <hi>Ro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bertus Sawyer</hi> Miles, Attorn. Dom. Regis nunc Generalis, qui pro codem Dom. Rege in hac parte ſequitur, in propria per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſona ſua von. hic in Cur. dict. Dom. Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gis coram ipſo Rege apud <hi>Weſtm.</hi> die Lunae prox. poſt quinden' S. Martini iſto codem term', &amp; pro eodem Dom. Rege dat. Cur. hic Intelligi &amp; Informa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ri, quod Major &amp; Communitas ac Cives Civitat. <hi>Lond.</hi> praed. per ſpacium unius Menſis jam ult. elapſ. &amp; amplius uſi fuerunt &amp; adhuc utuntur, ac clamant habere &amp; uti abſque aliquo Warranto ſive Regali Conceſſione infra Civitat. <hi>Lond.</hi> praed. &amp; Libertat. &amp; Praecinct. ejuſdem Civitat. diverſis Libertat. Pri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vileg. &amp; Francheſ. ſequen. videl. Fore de ſeipſis unum Corpus Corporat. &amp; Po<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liticum in nomine Majoris &amp; Civitat. ac Civium Civitat. <hi>London</hi> ac per idem nomen placitare &amp; implacitari, reſpon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dere &amp; reſponderi, ac etiam habere Vicecomit. Civitat. &amp; Comitat. Civi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tat. <hi>Lond.</hi> &amp; nominare &amp; eligere ex ſeipſis duas perſonas fore Vicecomit. Ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vitat. praed. &amp; Com. ejuſdem Civitat. Ac ill. ſic nominat. &amp; elect. praeſicere &amp; conſtituere Vic. Civit. praed. &amp; Com. ejuſdem Civitat. ad Execution. &amp; Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>torn. omnium Brevium, Billarum, &amp; Praeceptorum Dom. Regis pro Admini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtratione &amp; Executione Juſtic. infra Civit. praed. &amp; Com. ejuſdem Civit. exe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quend. faciend. ac ad faciend. &amp; exe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quend. omnia &amp; ſingula al. infra Civit. praed. &amp; Com. ejuſdem Civit. quae ad Officium Vic. faciend. pertinent. Ac etiam habere Vic. Com. <hi>Middleſex,</hi> &amp; nomi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nare,
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:95897:3"/>eligere &amp; conſtituere exſeipſis Vic. Com. <hi>Middleſex,</hi> pro eodem Com. ut Vicecomes inde deſervitur. ac omnia Brevia, Billas, &amp; praecepta Dom. Regis infra Com. <hi>Middleſex</hi> praed. pro Admi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſtratione &amp; Executione Juſtic. ibid. exequend. &amp; retorn. inde faciend. abſque aliqua Commiſſione ſive aliquibus Lite<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ris Patentibus à Dom. Rege inde ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tent. ſive obtinend. Ac etiam quod Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jor &amp; Aldermanni ejuſdem Civit. fuc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>runt Juſtic. Dom. Regis ad pacem in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fra Civit. praed. conſervand. ac ad Seſſiones pacis &amp; placita Coronae in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fra eandem Civit. tenend. ac ad om<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nes Felon. Riot. &amp; Conventic. illicit. infra Civit. praed. inquirend. audiend. &amp; terminand. Authoritate ipſorum propria, abſque aliqua Commiſſione, ſive al. Authoritate à Dom. Rege in ea parte conceſſ. ſive obtent. De quibus quidem omnibus &amp; ſingulis Libertat. Privileg. &amp; Francheſ. iidem Major &amp; Communitas ac Cives Civit. <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don</hi> praed. per totum tempus ſupra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dictum, ſupra dictum Dom. Regem nunc uſurpaverunt &amp; adhuc uſurpant, in dict. Dom. Regis nunc Contempt. Praerogativae ſuae Regiae grave damp<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>num &amp; praejudicium. <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>nde idem At<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tornat. dict. Dom. Regis nunc Gene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ral. pro eodem Dom. Rege pet. Advi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſament. Cur. hic in praemiſs. &amp; debit. Legis Proceſ. verſus Praefat. Major. &amp; Communitat. ac Cives Civit. <hi>Lond.</hi> praed. in hac parte fieri ad reſpon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dend. dict. Dom. Regi <hi>Quo Warran<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to</hi> clamant habere, uti &amp; gaudere Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bertat. Privileg. &amp; Francheſ. ſupra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dict. <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div xml:lang="eng" type="version">
               <pb n="1" facs="tcp:95897:2"/>
               <head>In Engliſh thus: <hi>The Information in</hi> Michaelmas <hi>Term, in the Thirty Third Year of</hi> Car. II. <hi>King of</hi> England, &amp;c.</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>Lond. ſſ. MEmorand'</hi> That <hi>Robert Sawyer</hi> Knight, our Lord the Kings At<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>torney General, who on this behalf proſecutes for our ſaid Lord the King, appears here in his own perſon in the Court of our ſaid Lord the King, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore the King himſelf at <hi>Weſtminſter</hi> on <hi>Munday</hi> next after the <hi>Quindene</hi> of St. <hi>Martin</hi> (<hi>viz.</hi> Nov. 27.) in the ſame Term; and for our ſaid Lord the King, gives this Court to underſtand and be in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>formed, That the Mayor and Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>monalty and Citizens of the City of <hi>London</hi> aforeſaid, for the ſpace of one month laſt paſt, and longer, have uſed, and do yet uſe, and claim to have and uſe (without any Warrant or Royal Grant) within the City of <hi>London</hi> aforeſaid, and the Liberties and Precincts of the ſaid City, divers Liberties, Priviledges, and Franchiſes following, to wit, To be of themſelves one Body Corporate and Politick, in the Name of the Mayor and Commonalty and Citizens of the City of <hi>London,</hi> and by the ſame Name to implead and be impleaded, to anſwer and be anſwered; And alſo to have a Sheriff of the City and County of the City of <hi>London,</hi> and to Nominate and Elect out of themſelves two perſons, <hi>One</hi> to be the Sheriff of the City aforeſaid, and of the County of the ſame City, and him ſo nominated and elected to prefer and conſtitute Sheriff of the City afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid and of the County of the ſaid City, for the Execution and Return of all Breve's, Bills, and Precepts of our Lord the King, for the adminiſtration and exe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cution of the Juſtice within the City
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:95897:3"/>aforeſaid, and County of the ſame City, to be executed and done, and to do and execute all and every the other things within the City aforeſaid, and County of the ſame, that belong to the Office of a Sheriff: And alſo to Nominate, Elect and Conſtitute <hi>Another</hi> perſon out of themſelves for the Sheriff of the Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty of <hi>Middleſex,</hi> for the ſaid County to ſerve as Sheriff for the ſame, and to exe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cute there and make return of all Breve's, Bills and Precepts of our Lord the King within the County of <hi>Middleſex</hi> afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, for the adminiſtration and execu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion of Juſtice, without any Commiſſion or Letters Patents obtained or to be ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tained from our Lord the King on that behalf: And alſo, that the Mayor and Aldermen of the ſaid City, have been Juſtices of our Lord the King to keep the Peace within the ſaid City, and to hold Seſſions of the Peace and Pleas of the Crown within the ſaid City, and all the Felonies, Riots and unlawful Conven<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ticles within the ſaid City, to enquire into, hear and determine by their own proper authority, without any Commiſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſion or other Authority from our Lord the King granted or obtained on that behalf. All and every of which Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>berties, Priviledges, and Franchiſes, the ſaid Mayor and Commonalty and Citi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>zens of the City of <hi>London</hi> aforeſaid, for all the ſaid time, have uſurped, and do ſtill uſurp over our ſaid Lord the King, to the contempt of our ſaid Lord the King, and to the great damage and pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>judice of his Prerogative Royal. Where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>upon the ſaid Attorney-General of our Lord the King, doth deſire for our ſaid Lord the King the Advice of this Court in the premiſſes, and due courſe of Law to be made againſt the ſaid Mayor and Commonalty and Citizens of the City of <hi>London</hi> aforeſaid on this behalf, to an<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſwer our ſaid Lord the King, <hi>By what Warrant</hi> they claim to have, uſe and enjoy the Liberties, Priviledges, and Franchiſes aforeſaid, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
         </div>
         <div type="legal_document">
            <pb n="3" facs="tcp:95897:3"/>
            <head>The PLEA. Major &amp; Communitas ac Cives Ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vit' <hi>London,</hi> ad Sectam Dom' Regis.</head>
            <div xml:lang="lat" type="version">
               <p>ET predicti Major &amp; Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>munitas ac Cives Civitatis <hi>London</hi> per <hi>Benedictum Brown</hi> Attornat' ſuu' ven' &amp; habito auditu Information' predict' querunt' ſe Colore ejuſdem Informationis gra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vit' fore vexat' &amp; inquietat' &amp; hoc minus juſte quia proteſtando quod In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>formatio predict' materia<expan>
                     <am>
                        <g ref="char:abque"/>
                     </am>
                     <ex>que</ex>
                  </expan> in eadem content' min' ſuffic' in Lege exiſt' ad-qua' quidem Informat' ipſi neceſſe non habent nec per Legem Terre te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>net' aliquo modo reſpondere pro Pla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cito tamen quoad libertat' Privileg' &amp; Franchiz' ſequen' <hi>(viz.)</hi> ipſos Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jor &amp; Communitas ac Cives Civit' <hi>London</hi> fore de ſeipſis unu' corpus Corporat' &amp; Politic' in re facto &amp; nomine per Nomen Majoris &amp; Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>munitat' ac Civiu' Civitat' <hi>London,</hi> ac per idem Nomen placitare &amp; im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>placitare reſpondere ac reſponderi in Informat' praedict' ſuperius ſpecificat' iidem Major &amp; Communitas ac Cives Civit' <hi>London</hi> dicunt quod dict' Domin' Rex nunc ipſos occaſione inde impetere ſeu occaſonare non debet quia dicunt quod praedict Civit' <hi>London</hi> eſt &amp; a tempore cujus con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trar' memoria' homin' non exiſt' fu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>it antiqua Civitas Quod<expan>
                     <am>
                        <g ref="char:abque"/>
                     </am>
                     <ex>que</ex>
                  </expan> Cives ejuſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dem Civit' ſunt &amp; à praedict' tempo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>re cujus contra memor' homin' non
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:95897:4"/>exiſt' fuerunt un' corpus corporat' &amp; Politic' in re facto &amp; nomine per nomen Majoris &amp; Communitat' ac Civium Civit' <hi>London</hi> ac per idem nomen per tot' tempus illud placita<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver' &amp; implacitat' fuerunt reſponder' &amp; reſpons' fuerunt, &amp; placitare &amp; implacitari, reſpondere ac reſponderi ac toto tempore ſupradicto uſi fuerunt &amp; conſuever' Quod<expan>
                     <am>
                        <g ref="char:abque"/>
                     </am>
                     <ex>que</ex>
                  </expan> in Magna Char<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ta de libertat' <hi>Angl'</hi> in Parliament' Domin' <hi>Henrici</hi> quondam Regis <hi>Angl'</hi> tertii apud <hi>Weſtm'</hi> in Comitat' <hi>Midd'</hi> Anno Regni ſui nono tent' edit' &amp; provis' continet' quod Civi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tas <hi>London</hi> habeat omnes libertat' ſuas antiquas &amp; conſuetud' ſuas &amp; iidem Major &amp; Communitas ac Cives Civit' <hi>London</hi> ulterius dicunt quod Domin' <hi>Edwardus</hi> quondam Rex <hi>Angl'</hi> tertius in Parliamento ſuo apud <hi>Weſtm'</hi> in Comit' <hi>Midd'</hi> Anno Regni ſui primo tent' per quandam Cartam ſuam de conſenſu Praelator' Comit' Baron' ac totius Communitat' Regni ſui in eodem Parliament' ſuo apud <hi>Weſtm'</hi> praedict' convocat' exiſten' ac Authoritat' ejuſdem Parliament' confirmavit tunc Civibus Civit' <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don</hi> praedict' libertat' ſubſequen' int' alia) habend' ſibi &amp; ſucceſſoribus ſuis in perpetuum, imprimis recitando: quod cu' in Magna Charta de liber<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tat' <hi>Angl'</hi> contineat' quod Civit' <hi>London</hi> habeat omn' libertat' ſuas antiquas &amp; conſuetud' ſuas; Et quod iidem Cives tempore confection' dictae Cartae ac temporibus Sancti <hi>Edwardi</hi> Regis &amp; Confeſſoris &amp; <hi>Willielmi</hi> Conqueſtoris &amp; al' Progenitor' dict' Regis <hi>Edwardi</hi> in divers' libertat'
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:95897:4"/>&amp; conſuetud' tam per Cartas ipſor' Progenitor' ſuor' quam ſuae Cartis ex antiqua conſuetud' habuiſſent, vo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>luit &amp; conceſſit idem Rex <hi>Edwardus</hi> tertius pro ſe &amp; Haeredibus ſuis per Cartam illam authoritat' praedict' quod iidem Cives habuerint Tiber<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tac' ſuas ſecund' form' Magn' Car<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tae ſupradict' &amp; quod pro aliqua perſonali tranſgr' vel Judicio perſo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nal' alicujus Miniſtri ejuſdem Civit' non caperet' libertat' Civit' ill' in manus ejaſdem Regis <hi>Edwardi</hi> tertii vel Hered' ſuor' ſed hujuſmodi Mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſter prout qualitas tranſgreſs' re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quiret puniet' prout per eandem Car<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tam geren' dat' apud <hi>Weſtm'</hi> prae<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dict' ſexto die <hi>Martii,</hi> Anno Regni dict' Regis <hi>Edwardi</hi> tertii primo ſu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pradict' ſub magno ſigillo ſuo <hi>Angl'</hi> ſigillat' hic in Cur' praelat' inter alia plenius apparet Et iidem Major &amp; Communitas ac Cives Civit' <hi>London</hi> ulterius dicunt quod ad inſtant' &amp; requiſit Communitat' Regni <hi>Angl'</hi> in Parliamento Domin' <hi>Ricardi</hi> nuper Regis <hi>Angl'</hi> ſecundo poſt Conqueſt' apud <hi>Weſtm'</hi> praedict' Anno Regni ſui ſeptimo tent' aſſemblat' pro ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jore quiete &amp; pace int' ligeos ejuſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dem nuper Regis faciend' &amp; pro bono publico omnes Conſuetud' libertat' Privileg' &amp; franch' Civit' praedict' tunc Civibus Civit' illius &amp; eor' ſucceſſor' licet uſi non fuerint vel abuſi fuerint eiſdem Authorit' ejuſdem Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liament' ratificat' &amp; confirmat' fuer' Quod<expan>
                     <am>
                        <g ref="char:abque"/>
                     </am>
                     <ex>que</ex>
                  </expan> Domin' <hi>Henricus</hi> nuper Rex <hi>Angl'</hi> ſextus per litteras ſuas pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tent' ſub magno ſigillo ſuo <hi>Angl'</hi> ſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gillat' geren' dat' apud <hi>Weſtm'</hi> prae<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dict'
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:95897:5"/>viceſimo ſexto die <hi>Octobr'</hi> An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>no Regn' ſui viceſimo tertio quas iidem Major &amp; Communitas &amp; Cives Ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vit' <hi>London</hi> hic in Cur' proferunt pro ſe, Heredibus et Succeſſoribus ſuis confirmavit Majori et Commu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nitat' ac Civibus Civit' <hi>London</hi> et ſucceſſor' ſuis omnes et ſingulas ſuas' libertat' franc' et liberas Conſue<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tud' adeo integras et illeſas ſicut eas unquam aliquo tempore Progenitor' ejuſdem nuper Regis <hi>Henrici</hi> ſexti melius, quietius et liber' habuiſſent et tenuiſſent prout per eaſdem litteras patent' int' alia plenius apparet Quod<expan>
                     <am>
                        <g ref="char:abque"/>
                     </am>
                     <ex>que</ex>
                  </expan> Domin' <hi>Edwardus</hi> nuper Rex <hi>Ang'</hi> quartus per litteras ſuas pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tent' ſub magno ſigillo ſuo <hi>Angl'</hi> ſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gillat' geren' dat' apud <hi>Weſtm'</hi> prae<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dict' Nono die <hi>Novembr'</hi> Anno Regn' ſui ſecundo quas iidem Major et Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>munitas ac Cives Civit' <hi>London</hi> hic in Cur' proferunt pro ſe et Heredi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bus ſuis confirmavit Majori et Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>munitat' ac Civib. Civit. <hi>London</hi> et ſucceſſoribus ſuis in perpetu. omn. et ſingulas ſuas libertat. Franc. et li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>beras Conſuetud. adeo integr. et illaeſ. ſicut eas unquam aliquo tempore Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>genitor. ejuſdem nuper Reg. <hi>Edwar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>di</hi> quarti melius, quietius et liber. ha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>buiſſent et tenuiſſent Et ulterius idem nuper Rex <hi>Edwardus</hi> quartus per eaſdem litteras ſuas patent. conceſſit eiſdem Majori et Communitat. ac Ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vibus quod licet ipſi vel Predeceſſor. ſui aut Major et Alderman. Civit. praedict. vel Predeceſſor. ſui praean<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tea vel Succeſſor. ſui extunc im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſter. aliqua vel aliquibus libertat. quietant. conceſſ. ordinat. Articulor. ſeu liberar. Conſuetud. aut alior. in
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:95897:5"/>eiſdem litteris patent' ejuſdem nuper Regis <hi>Edwardi</hi> quarti ſeu al' literis ſuis aut Progenitor' ſuor' quondam Reg' <hi>Angl'</hi> eiſdem Majori &amp; Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>munitat' conceſs' content' aliquo Caſu emergente plene non uſi vel abuſi fue<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rint: Noluit tamen idem nuper Rex <hi>Edwardus</hi> quartus quod propt' hoc ipſi Major &amp; Communitat' Alder<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mann' &amp; Cives ſeu Succeſſoribus ſui forisfactur' aliquor' praemiſs' incurre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rent ſed quod ipſi &amp; eor' Succeſſor' univerſis &amp; ſingulis libertat' quie<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tant' conceſs' ordinat' Articulis, libe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ris Conſuetud' &amp; quibuſcun<expan>
                     <am>
                        <g ref="char:abque"/>
                     </am>
                     <ex>que</ex>
                  </expan> al' in Cartis &amp; litteris praedict' content. to<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>taliter non uſis vel etiam abuſis &amp; eor. quolibet extunc de caetero plene &amp; libere gauderent &amp; eis uterent. ſine impetition. vel impediment' ejuſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dem nuper Regis ſeu Hered. ſuor. Juſtic. Eſcator. Vicecom. aut al. Balliv. ſeu Miniſtr. ipſius nuper Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gis vel al. quorumcun<expan>
                     <am>
                        <g ref="char:abque"/>
                     </am>
                     <ex>que</ex>
                  </expan> prout per eaſdem litteras patent, ejuſdem nu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>per Regis <hi>Edwardi</hi> quarti hic in Cur. prolat. int. alia plenius apparet. Quod<expan>
                     <am>
                        <g ref="char:abque"/>
                     </am>
                     <ex>que</ex>
                  </expan> Domin. <hi>Henricus</hi> nuper Rex <hi>Angl.</hi> Septimus per litteras ſuas pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tent. ſub magno ſigillo ſuo <hi>Angl.</hi> ſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gillat. geren. dat. apud <hi>Weſtm.</hi> prae<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dict. viceſſimo tertio die <hi>Julii</hi> Anno Regniſui Viceſſimo, quas iidem Major &amp; Communitas ac Cives Civit. <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don</hi> hic in Cur. proferunt pro ſe He<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>redibus &amp; Succeſſoribus ſuis Ratifi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cavit &amp; Confirmavit Majori &amp; Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>munitat. ac Civibus Civit' <hi>London</hi> &amp; eor. Succeſſor. omnia &amp; ſingula li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bertat. privileg. quietant. &amp; liberas Conſuetud. quibus ipſi Major Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>munitas &amp; Cives ſeu Predeceſſor. ſui habere, exercere ſeu gaudere conſue<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viſſent
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:95897:6"/>vel uſi fuiſſent aut deveniſſent adeo plene, plan. &amp; integre ac ſi ac omnia &amp; ſingula ſeparatim &amp; verbat. in eiſdem litteris patent. expreſs. de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>clarat. &amp; manifeſtat. eſſent &amp; fuiſſent, prout per eaſdem litteras patent int<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>alia plenius apparet. Et iidem Major &amp; Communitas ac Cives Civit. <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don</hi> ulterius dicunt quod Domin. <hi>Ja<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cobus</hi> nuper Rex <hi>Angl.</hi> &amp;c. per lit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teras ſuas Patent. ſub Magno ſigillo ſuo <hi>Angl.</hi> ſigillat. geren. dat. apud Honorem ſuu. de <hi>Hampton-Court</hi> Viceſſimo quarto die <hi>Septembris</hi> An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>no Regni ſui <hi>Angl.</hi> ſexte, quas iidem Major &amp; Communitas ac Cives Civit. <hi>London</hi> hic in Cur. proſerunt reci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tando quod cum quamplurimi Proge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nitores ipſius nuper Regis quondam Reges <hi>Angl.</hi> de gratia ſua ſpecial. ac progratis laudabil. multiplicib. &amp; contin. ſervit. per Majorem &amp; Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>munitat. ac Cives Civit. <hi>London</hi> et Praedeceſſor' ſuos temporibus retract. fact. et impenſ. Necnon pro diverſ. al. urgent. cauſis et conſideration. cos ſeparatim moven. dediſſent conceſſiſſent et confirmaſſent Majori et Commu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nitat. ac Civib. Civit. <hi>London</hi> prae<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dict. et Succeſſor. ſuis diverſ. liber<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tat. Privileg. Franch. Immunitat. Authorit. Juriſdiction. Ordinat. Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſuetud. et quietant. prout, per ſepa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rat. litteras Patent. Progenitor. et Predeceſſor. ſuor. quondam Regum <hi>Angl.</hi> plenius et manifeſtius lique<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lat et apparebat. Idem nuper Rex <hi>Jacobus</hi> pro et in conſiderat. ſum. fidelitat. conſtant. et prompt. et lau<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dabil. ſervit. per Major. et Commu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nitat. ac Cives. Civit. <hi>London</hi> prae<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dict. eidem nuper Regi in ipſ. Regn. ſui primis Auſpiciis et continue uſ<expan>
                     <am>
                        <g ref="char:abque"/>
                     </am>
                     <ex>que</ex>
                  </expan> tunc manifeſt. et fideliſſim. fact. et impenſ. omnes et ſingulas Litteras Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tent.
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:95897:6"/>Cartas et confirmac. Praeclariſſ. Progenitor. et Succeſſor. ſuor. eiſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dem Majori et Communitat. ac Ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vib. Civit. <hi>London</hi> praedict. et ſuc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſſor. ſuis per quaecunque nomina in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>corporat. ante tunc tempora fact. con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſſ. ſeu confirmat. ac omnes et ſingu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>las donac. conceſſ. confirmac. reſtitut. conſuetud. ordinac. explanac. arti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cul. et omnes al. res quaſcun<expan>
                     <am>
                        <g ref="char:abque"/>
                     </am>
                     <ex>que</ex>
                  </expan> in quibuſcun<expan>
                     <am>
                        <g ref="char:abque"/>
                     </am>
                     <ex>que</ex>
                  </expan> litteris paten. ſive Cartae quorumcun<expan>
                     <am>
                        <g ref="char:abque"/>
                     </am>
                     <ex>que</ex>
                  </expan> Progenitor. Predeceſſ. aut Anteceſſor. ſuor. Regn. <hi>Angl.</hi> Necnon omnia et ſingula in dict. lit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teris patent. Chartis conceſſ. confirmat. ſeu eor. aliquibus content. recitat. ſpecifac. confirmat. ſeu explanat. Ac omnia et ſingula Juriſdiction. Autho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ritat. Privileg. Libertat. Franch. Quietanc. Immunitat. liberas Conſue<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tud. et Hereditament. quaecun<expan>
                     <am>
                        <g ref="char:abque"/>
                     </am>
                     <ex>que</ex>
                  </expan> quae praedict. Major et Communitas ac Cives Civit. <hi>London</hi> praedict. vel Predeceſſor. ſui per Nomen Major. et Communitat. ac Civium Civit. <hi>London</hi> ſeu per Nomen Major. et Aldermann. Civit. <hi>London</hi> ſeu per Nomen Majoris Civium et Communi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tat. Civit. <hi>London</hi> ſeu per Nomen Majoris et Civium Civit. <hi>London</hi> ſeu per Nomen Majoris et Commu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nitat. Civit. <hi>London</hi> ſeu per Nomen Civium Civit. <hi>London</hi> ſeu per no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men Baron. <hi>London</hi> ſeu per Nomen Baron. Civit. <hi>London</hi> ſeu per ali<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quod al. nomen quodcunque ratione ſeu vigore aliquar. litterar. patent. Cartar. ſeu confirmac. aliquor. Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>genitor. Praedeceſſor. aut Anteceſſor. ejuſdem nuper Regis <hi>Jacobi</hi> quon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dam Regis <hi>Angl.</hi> aliquo tempore vel aliquib. temporib. habuiſſent ſeu ra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tionabilit.
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:95897:7"/>uſi fuiſſent aut exercuiſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent rata habuit et grata ac pro ſe et Hered. et Succeſſor. ſuis acceptavit et approbavit ac ea omnia et ſingula prefat. Major. et Communitat. ac Civib. Civit. <hi>London</hi> praedict. et eor. Succeſſorib. per eaſdem litteras ſuas patent. ratificavit et confirmavit ha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bend. tenend. gaudend. et exercend. omnia et ſingula praemiſſ. eiſdem Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jor. et Communitat. ac Civibus Ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vit. <hi>London</hi> praedict. et Succeſſori<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bus ſuis in perpetuum adeo plene, li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bere et integre ac in tam amplis modo et forma ac ſi ſeparatim, ſin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gulatim et nominatim in litteris pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tent. ill. expreſſ. nominat. declarat. recitat. et manifeſt. eſſent et fuiſſent, prout per eaſdem litteras patent. in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter alia plenius apparet. Quodque Domin. <hi>Carolus</hi> primus nuper Rex <hi>Angl'</hi> &amp;c. per litteras ſuas patent. ſub magno ſigillo ſuo <hi>Angl.</hi> ſigillat. geren. dat. apud <hi>Weſtm.</hi> praedict. decimo octavo die <hi>Octobris</hi> Anno regni ſui quartodecimo, quas iidem Major et Communitas ac Cives Civit. <hi>London</hi> hic in Cur. proferunt om<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nia et ſingula Privileg. Libertat. Franc. Quietanc. Immunitat. et li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>beras Conſuetud. quaecun<expan>
                     <am>
                        <g ref="char:abque"/>
                     </am>
                     <ex>que</ex>
                  </expan> que prae<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dict. Major et Communitas ac Cives Civit. <hi>London</hi> praedict. vel Praede<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſſor. ſui per Nomen Majoris et Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>munitat. ac Civium Civit. <hi>London</hi> ſeu per Nomen Majoris et Aldermann. Civium et Communitat. <hi>London</hi> ſeu per Nomen Majoris et Civium Civit. <hi>London</hi> ſeu per Nomen Majoris et Communitat. Civit. <hi>London</hi> ſeu per Nomen Civium Civit. <hi>London</hi> ſeu per Nomen Baron. <hi>London</hi> ſeu per
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:95897:7"/>Nomen Baron. Civit. <hi>London</hi> ſeu per aliquod al. nomen quodcun<expan>
                     <am>
                        <g ref="char:abque"/>
                     </am>
                     <ex>que</ex>
                  </expan> ra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tione ſeu vigore litterar. patent. Cartar. ſeu confirmac. in eiſdem lit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teris patent. dicti nuper Regis <hi>Ca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>roli</hi> primi mentionat. vel uſu vel praeſcriptione aut alio legal. modo aliquo tempore vel aliquibus tempo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ribus ante hoc habuiſſent ſeu ratio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nabiliter uſi fuiſſent aut exercuiſſent rat. haben. et grata ac pro ſe here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dibus et ſucceſſoribus ſuis accepta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vit et approbavit, ac ea omnia et ſin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gula praefat. Majori et Communitat. ac Civibus Civit. <hi>London</hi> et eor. Succeſſor. per eaſdem litteras ſuas patent. ratificavit et confirmavit, pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ut per litteras patent. ill. int. alia plenius liquet et apparet. Quodque praedict. Domin. Rex nunc per lit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teras ſuas patent. ſub magno ſigillo ſuo <hi>Angl.</hi> ſigillat. geren. dat. apud <hi>Weſtm.</hi> praedict. viceſimo quarto die <hi>Junii</hi> Anno regni ſui decimo quinto, quas iidem Major et Communitas ac Cives Civit. <hi>London</hi> hic in Cur. proferunt pro ipſo Rege, Heredibus et Succeſſoribus ſuis ratificavit et confirmavit Major et Communitat. ac Civibus Civit. <hi>London</hi> et ſucceſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſor. ſuis omnia et ſingula Juriſdi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ction. Authoritat. Privileg. Liber<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tat. Franch. Quietanc. Immunitat. et Conſuetud. quecun<expan>
                     <am>
                        <g ref="char:abque"/>
                     </am>
                     <ex>que</ex>
                  </expan> que praefat. Major et Communitas ac Cives Civit. <hi>London</hi> vel Praedeceſſor. ſui per Nomen Major. et Communitat. ac Civium Civit. <hi>London</hi> ſeu per No<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men Majoris Aldermannor. Civium et Communitat. <hi>London</hi> ſeu per Nomen Majoris et Civium Civit. <hi>London</hi> ſeu per Nomen Major. et Communit. Civit.
<pb n="12" facs="tcp:95897:8"/>
                  <hi>London</hi> ſeu per Nomen Civium Civit. <hi>London,</hi> ſeu per Nomen Baron. <hi>London,</hi> ſeu per Nomen Baron. Civitat. <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don,</hi> ſeu per aliquod al' Nomen quod<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cun<expan>
                     <am>
                        <g ref="char:abque"/>
                     </am>
                     <ex>que</ex>
                  </expan> ratione vel vigore Litterar. patent. cartar. ſeu confirmat. in eiſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dem litteris patent. dicti Domin. Regis nunc praementionat. vel alicujus ſeu aliquar. uſus vel uſu. praeſcripti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on. vel praeſcriptionum ſeu al. legali modo quocun<expan>
                     <am>
                        <g ref="char:abque"/>
                     </am>
                     <ex>que</ex>
                  </expan> aliquo tempore, vel aliquibus temporibus ante tunc habu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>iſſent ſeu rationabilit. uſi fuiſſent, ſeu exercuiſſent habend. tenend. gaudend. &amp; exercend. omnia &amp; ſingula prae<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſs. praedict. eiſdem Majori &amp; Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>munitat. ac Civibus Civitat. <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don</hi> praedict. &amp; Succeſſoribus ſuis in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>perpetuum adeo plene libere &amp; inte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gre ac in tam amplio modo &amp; for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ma prout in eiſdem Litteris patent. ſuperius mentionat. fore data ſive con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſſa aut alit. uſu praeſcription. vel al. legali modo ſeu jure quocun<expan>
                     <am>
                        <g ref="char:abque"/>
                     </am>
                     <ex>que</ex>
                  </expan> ante tunc reſpective habit. obtent. ſive ga<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viſa fuiſſent ac ſi ſeparatim ſingula<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tim &amp; nominatim in et per dictas litteras patent. ipſius Domin. Regis nunc expreſs. nominat. declarat. con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſſ. &amp; manifeſta eſſent et fuiſſent prout per eaſdem Litteras Patent. inter alia plenius apparet. Et eo Warranto iidem Major &amp; Communi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tat. ac Cives Civitat. <hi>London</hi> per tempus in Informatione praedicta ſu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>perius ſpecifac. uſi fuer. &amp; adhuc utunt. ac clamant habere &amp; uti Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bertat. Privileg. &amp; Franch. fore de ſeipſis unum Corpus Corporat. &amp; po<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>litic. in re facto &amp; Nomine per No<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men Majoris &amp; Communitat. ac Ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vium Civitat' <hi>London,</hi> ac per idem Nomen placitare &amp; implacitari, re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpondere ac reſponderi prout eis bene
<pb n="13" facs="tcp:95897:8"/>licuit &amp; licet. Abſ<expan>
                     <am>
                        <g ref="char:abque"/>
                     </am>
                     <ex>que</ex>
                  </expan> hoc quod iidem Major &amp; Communitas ac Cives Civi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tat. <hi>London</hi> de Libertat. Privileg. &amp; Franch. ill. ſuper dictum Domin. Regem nunc per tempus praedict. in Informatione praedict. ſuperius ſpeci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fac. <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>ſurpaver. ſeu <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>ſurpant prout per Information. ill. pro dicto Domin. Rege nunc ſuperius ſuppoſuit. Quae omnia &amp; ſingula iidem Major ac Communitas ac Cives Civitat. <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don</hi> parat. ſunt verificare, unde petit Judicium; Et quod Libertat. Privileg. &amp; Franch. ill. eis &amp; Succeſſoribus ſuis in perpetuu. deinceps allocent. &amp; ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>judicent. &amp; quod ipſi quoad praemiſs. ill. ab hac Cur. dimittant. <hi>&amp;c.</hi> Et iidem Major &amp; Communitas ac Cives Civit. <hi>London,</hi> quoad Libertat. Pri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vileg. &amp; Franch. ſequen. <hi>viz.</hi> ipſos habere. Vicecom. Civit. &amp; Com. Civit. <hi>London</hi> &amp; Vicecom. <hi>Midd.</hi> &amp; nomi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nare et eligere ex ſeipſis ſuas perſonas fore Vicecom. Civit. praedict. et Com. ejuſdem Civit. et Vicecom. <hi>Midd.</hi> ac ill. ſic nominat. et Elect. praeficere et conſtituere Vicecom. Civit. praedict. et Com. ejuſdem Civit. et Vicecom. <hi>Midd.</hi> ac ut Vicecom. Civit. praedict. et in Com. ejuſdem Civit. ad execut. et Retorn. omniu. breviu. Bill. et Prae<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cept. Domin. Regis pro Adminiſtrati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>one et execut. Juſtic. infra Civit. prae<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dict. et Com. ejuſdem Civit. exe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quend. faciend. quae ad Officiu. Vice<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>com. faciend. pertinent ac ad faciend. et exequend. omnia et ſingula alia infra Civit. praedict. &amp; Com. ejuſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dem Civit. que ad officiu. Vicecom. fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ciend. pertinent, acout Vicecom. Com.
<pb n="14" facs="tcp:95897:9"/>
                  <hi>Midd.</hi> pro eodem Com. deſervitur. ac omnia Brevia, Bill. &amp; Praecept. Domin. Regis infra Com. <hi>Midd.</hi> prae<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dict. pro Adminiſtratione &amp; Exe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cutione Juſtitiae ibidem exequend. &amp; retorn. inde faciend. quae ad Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ficium Vicecom. faciend. pertinen. Dicunt quod Dictus Domin. Rex nunc ipſos Majorem &amp; Communitat. ac Cives Civitat. <hi>London</hi> occaſione inde impetere ſeu occaſonare non debet, quia dicunt quod praedict. Civit. <hi>London</hi> eſt &amp; a tempore cujus con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trar. memoria. homin. non exiſt. fuit antiqua Civitas &amp; antiqu. Comit. de ſe Quod<expan>
                     <am>
                        <g ref="char:abque"/>
                     </am>
                     <ex>que</ex>
                  </expan> praedict. Com. <hi>Midd.</hi> per totum tempus praedict. fuit &amp; eſt antiquus Comit. Quod<expan>
                     <am>
                        <g ref="char:abque"/>
                     </am>
                     <ex>que</ex>
                  </expan> Cives ejuſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dem Civit. ſunt &amp; a praedict. tem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pore cujus contrar. memor. homin. non exiſt. fuer. un. corpus corpo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rat. &amp; politicu. tam per Nomen Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jor. &amp; Communitat. ac Civium Ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vit. <hi>London</hi> quam per Nomen Civi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>um <hi>London</hi> Quod<expan>
                     <am>
                        <g ref="char:abque"/>
                     </am>
                     <ex>que</ex>
                  </expan> Domin. <hi>Johan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nes</hi> quondam Rex <hi>Angl.</hi> per litte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ras ſuas patent. ſub magno ſigillo ſuo <hi>Angl.</hi> ſigillat. geren. dat. apud bonam Villam ſuper <hi>Tokam,</hi> quin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to die <hi>Julii,</hi> Anno Regni ſui primo, quas iidem Major &amp; Communitat. ac Cives Civitat. <hi>London</hi> hic in Cur. proferunt, conceſſit Civibus <hi>London</hi> praedict. Vicecomit. <hi>London</hi> &amp; de <hi>Midd.</hi> cum omnibus rebus &amp; conſue<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tudinibus que pertinebant ad prae<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dict. Vicecom. infra Civit. &amp; extra, per terras &amp; per aquas habend. &amp; tenend. eis in perpetuum. Et praete<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rea idem Domin. Rex <hi>Johannes</hi> per litteras ſuas patent. praedict. con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſſit eiſdem Civibus <hi>London</hi> quod ipſi de ſeipſis facerent Vicecom. quoſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cun<expan>
                     <am>
                        <g ref="char:abque"/>
                     </am>
                     <ex>que</ex>
                  </expan> voluerint &amp; amoverent quando
<pb n="15" facs="tcp:95897:9"/>voluerint prout per eaſdem litteras patent. inter alia plenius apparet. Quod<expan>
                     <am>
                        <g ref="char:abque"/>
                     </am>
                     <ex>que</ex>
                  </expan> in Magna Charta de liberta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tibus <hi>Angl.</hi> in Parliament. Domin. <hi>Henrici</hi> quondam Regis <hi>Angl.</hi> tertii apud <hi>Weſtm.</hi> in Com. <hi>Midd.</hi> Anno regni ſui nono tent. edit. &amp; proviſ. continet. quod Civit. <hi>London</hi> ha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>beat omnes libertat. ſuas antiquas &amp; conſuetud. ſuas. Et iidem Major &amp; Communitas, ac Cives Civit. <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don</hi> ulterius dicunt quod idem Do<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>min. Rex <hi>Henricus</hi> tertius per lit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teras ſuas patent. ſub magno ſigillo ſuo <hi>Angl.</hi> ſigillat. geren. dat. apud <hi>Weſtm.</hi> praedict. decimo octavo die <hi>Februarii</hi> Anno Regni ſui undecimo quas iidem Major &amp; Communitas ac Cives Civit. <hi>London</hi> hic in Cur. proferunt, confirmavit Civibus <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don</hi> Vicecom. <hi>London</hi> &amp; de <hi>Midd.</hi> cum omnibus rebus &amp; conſuetudinib. quae pertineb. ad praedict. Vicecom. infra Civitat. &amp; extra, per terras &amp; per aquas prout per eaſdem litteras patent. int. al. plenius apparet. Quod<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>que Domin. <hi>Edwardus</hi> quondam Rex <hi>Angl.</hi> tertius in Parliament. ſuo apud <hi>Weſtm'</hi> tent. in Com. <hi>Midd.</hi> Anno regni ſui primo tent. per quandam Cartam ſuam de aſſenſu Praelator. Comit. Baron ac totius Communitat. regni ſui in eodem Parliamento ſuo apud <hi>Weſtm.</hi> praedict. convocat. exi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſten. ac Authoritate ejuſdem Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>menti confirmavit tunc Civibus Civit. <hi>London</hi> praedict. libertat. ſubſequen. int. al. habend. ſibi &amp; Succeſſoribus ſuis in perpetuum. Imprimis recitando quod cum in Magna Charta de libertat. <hi>Angl.</hi> contineat. quod Civitas <hi>London</hi>
                  <pb n="16" facs="tcp:95897:10"/>habeat omnes libertat. ſuas antiquas et conſuetud. ſuas. Et quod iidem Cives tempore confection. dictae Cartae ac temporibus ſancti <hi>Edwardi</hi> Regis et Confeſſoris, et <hi>Willielmi</hi> Conqueſtor. et al. Progenitor. dicti Regis <hi>Edwardi</hi> tertii diverſas libertat. et conſuetud. tamper Cartas ipſor. Progenitor. ſuor. quam ſine Cartis ex antiqua conſuetud. habuiſſent, voluit et conceſſit idem Rex <hi>Edwardus</hi> tertius pro ſe et Heredibus ſuis per Cartam ill. authoritat. prae<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dict. quod idem Cives haberent Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bertat. ſuas ſecund. formam magn. Car<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tae ſupradict. Et quod pro aliqua per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſonal. tranſgr. vel Judicio Perſonal. alicujus Miniſtri ejuſdem Civit. non caperet. libertas Civit. ill. in manu ejuſdem Regis <hi>Edwardi</hi> tertii vel Hered. ſuor. ſed hujuſmodi Miniſter prout qualitas tranſgr. requireret pu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niretur prout per eandem Cartam geren. dat. apud <hi>Weſtm.</hi> praedict. ſexto die <hi>martii</hi> Anno Regni dicti Regis <hi>Edwardi</hi> tertii primo ſupradict. ſub magno ſigillo ſuo <hi>Angl.</hi> ſigillat. hic in Cur. prolat. int. alia plenius apparet. Et iidem Major et Commu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nitas ac Cives Civit. <hi>London</hi> ulte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rius dicunt quod ad Inſtant. et re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quiſition. Communitat' Regni <hi>Angl.</hi> in Parliamento Domin. <hi>Ricardi</hi> nuper Regis <hi>Angl.</hi> Secundi poſt Conqueſtum apud <hi>Weſtm.</hi> praedict. Anno Regni ſui ſeptimo tent. aſſemblat. pro ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jore quiet' et pace inter ligeos ejuſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dem nuper Regis fovend. et pro bo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>no publico omnes Conſuetud. Libertat. Privileg. et Franch. Civit. praedict. tunc Civibus Civitat. illius et eor. Succeſſoribus, licet uſi non fuerint vel abuſi fuerint eiſdem Authoritat. ejuſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dem
<pb n="17" facs="tcp:95897:10"/>Parliament. ratificat. &amp; confir<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mat. fuer. Quod<expan>
                     <am>
                        <g ref="char:abque"/>
                     </am>
                     <ex>que</ex>
                  </expan> Dominus <hi>Henri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cus</hi> nuper Rex <hi>Angl.</hi> ſextus per lit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teras ſuas patent. ſub magno ſigillo ſuo <hi>Angl.</hi> ſigillat. geren. dat. apud <hi>Weſtm.</hi> praedict. viceſimo ſexto die <hi>Octobris,</hi> Anno Regni ſui viceſimo tertio quas iidem Major &amp; Commu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nitas ac Cives Civit. <hi>London</hi> hic in Cur. proferunt pro ſe Heredibus &amp; Succeſſoribus ſuis confirmavit Majori &amp; Communitat. ac Civibus Civit. <hi>London</hi> et Succeſſoribus ſuis omnes et ſingulas ſuas libertat. franch. et li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>beras Conſuetud. adeo integras et illeſas ſicut eas unquam aliquo tem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pore Progenitor. ejuſdem nuper Regis <hi>Henrici</hi> ſexti melius, quietius et li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ber. habuiſſent et tenuiſſent prout per eaſdem litteras patent. int. al. ple<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nius apparet. Quod<expan>
                     <am>
                        <g ref="char:abque"/>
                     </am>
                     <ex>que</ex>
                  </expan> Domin. <hi>Edwar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dus</hi> nuper Rex <hi>Angl.</hi> quartus per lit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teras ſuas patent. ſub magno ſigillo ſuo <hi>Angl.</hi> ſigillat geren. dat. apud <hi>Weſtm.</hi> praedict. nono die <hi>Novembr.</hi> Anno Regni ſui ſecundo quas iidem Major et Communitas ac Cives Civit. <hi>London</hi> hic in Cur. proferunt pro ſe et Heredibus ſuis confirmavit Majori et Communitat. ac Civibus Civit. <hi>London</hi> et Succeſſoribus ſuis in per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>petuum omnes et ſingulas ſuas liber<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tat. franch. et liberas Conſuetud. adeo integr. et illeſ. ſicut eas un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quam aliquo tempore Progenitor. ejuſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dem nuper Regis <hi>Edwardi</hi> quarti me<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lius, quietius et liber. habuiſſent et te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nuiſſent Et ulterius idem nuper Rex <hi>Edwardus</hi> quartus per eaſdem litte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ras ſuas patent. conceſſit eiſdem Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jori et Communitat. ac Civibus, quod licet ipſi vel Predeceſſores ſui aut Major et Aldermann. Civit. praedict. vel Praedeceſſor. ſui praeantea vel Suc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſſores ſui extunc impoſterum aliqua vel aliquibus libertat. quietant. con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſſ.
<pb facs="tcp:95897:11"/>Ordination. Articulor. ſeu li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>berar. Conſuetudin. aut alior. in eiſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dem Litteris Patentibus ejuſdem nu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>per Regis <hi>Edwardi</hi> quarti ſeu al. Litteris ſuis aut Progenitor. ſuor. quondam Regum <hi>Angl.</hi> eiſdem Majori &amp; Communitat. conceſs. content. ali<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quo caſu emergente plene non uſi vel abuſi fuerint. Noluit tamen idem nu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>per Rex. <hi>Edwardus</hi> quartus. quod propt. hoc. ipſi Major &amp; Communitas Alderman. &amp; Cives ſeu Succeſſor. ſui forisfactur. aliquor. premiſſor. in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>current ſed quod ipſi &amp; eorum Suc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſſor. <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>niverſis &amp; ſingulis libertat. quietant. conceſs. ordinat. Articulis Liberis Conſuetud. &amp; quibuſcun<expan>
                     <am>
                        <g ref="char:abque"/>
                     </am>
                     <ex>que</ex>
                  </expan> al. in Cartis &amp; litteris praedict. con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tent. totalit. non uſis vel etiam abuſis, &amp; eor. quolibet extunc de caetero ple<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ne &amp; libere gauderent &amp; eis ute<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rent. ſine impetatione vel impediment. ejuſdem nuper Regis ſeu Hered. ſuor. Juſtic. Eſcaetor. Viceom. aut al. Balliv. ſeu Miniſtr. ipſius nuper Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gis vel alior. quorumcun<expan>
                     <am>
                        <g ref="char:abque"/>
                     </am>
                     <ex>que</ex>
                  </expan> prout per eaſdem Litteras patent. ejuſdem nu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>per Regis <hi>Edwardi</hi> quarti hic in Cur. Prolat. int. al. plenius apparet. Quod<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>que Domin. <hi>Henricus</hi> nuper Rex <hi>Angl.</hi> Septimus per Litteras ſuas Patent. ſub Magno ſigillo ſuo <hi>Angl.</hi> Sigillat. geren. dat. apud <hi>Weſtm.</hi> praedict. Viceſimo tertio die <hi>Julii</hi> An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>no Regni ſui Viceſimo, quas iidem Major &amp; Communitas ac Cives Civit. <hi>London</hi> hic in Cur. proferunt pro ſe Hered. &amp; Succeſſoribus ſuis ratifi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cavit &amp; confirmavit Majori &amp; Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>munitat. ac Civibus Civit. <hi>London,</hi> &amp; eorum Succeſſoribus omnia &amp; ſin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gula Libertat. Privileg. quietant. &amp; liberas conſuetudines quibus ipſi Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jor Communitas &amp; Cives ſeu Pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>deceſſor. ſui habere, exercere ſeu gau<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dere conſueviſſent vel uſt fuiſſent aut
<pb n="18" facs="tcp:95897:11"/>debuiſſent aut plene, plane &amp; integre ac ſi ea omnia &amp; ſingula ſeparatim &amp; verbatim in eiſdem Litteris Patent expreſs' declarat' &amp; manifeſtat' eſſent &amp; fuiſſent prout per eaſdem Litte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ras Patent' inter alia plenius appa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ret. Quod<expan>
                     <am>
                        <g ref="char:abque"/>
                     </am>
                     <ex>que</ex>
                  </expan> Domin' <hi>Henricus</hi> nuper Rex <hi>Angl'</hi> Octavus per Litteras ſuas Patent. ſub magno ſigillo ſuo <hi>Angl'</hi> ſigillat' geren' dat' apud <hi>Weſtm'</hi> prae<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dict duodecimo Die <hi>Julii</hi> Anno Regni ſui quinto, quas iidem Major &amp; Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>munitas ac Cives Civit' <hi>London</hi> hic in Cur' proferunt omnes conceſſiones &amp; al, quaecun<expan>
                     <am>
                        <g ref="char:abque"/>
                     </am>
                     <ex>que</ex>
                  </expan> in praedict' Litteris Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tent' praedict' Domin' Regis <hi>Johannis</hi> ſuperius ſpecificat' content' quod ipſe Rege <hi>Henrico</hi> octavo &amp; Heredibus ſuis, Majori &amp; Communitat' ac Civi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bus Civitat' <hi>London</hi> &amp; Succeſſori<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bus ſuis Ratificavit &amp; Confirmavit, prout per eaſdem Litteras Patent' ejuſdem nuper Regis <hi>Henrici</hi> Octavi inter alia plenius apparet. Quod<expan>
                     <am>
                        <g ref="char:abque"/>
                     </am>
                     <ex>que</ex>
                  </expan> Dom' <hi>Edwardus</hi> nuper Rex <hi>Angl'</hi> Sextus per Litteras ſuas Patent' ſub magno figillo ſuo <hi>Angl'</hi> ſigillat' geren' dat' apud <hi>Weſtm'</hi> praedict' Viceſimo pri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mo die <hi>Februarii</hi> Anno Regni ſui Se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cundo, quas iidem Major &amp; Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>munitas ac Cives Civit' <hi>London</hi> hic in Cur' proferunt omnes conceſſion' &amp; al' quaecun<expan>
                     <am>
                        <g ref="char:abque"/>
                     </am>
                     <ex>que</ex>
                  </expan> in praedict' Litteris Patent' dicti Domin' Regis <hi>Johan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nis</hi> ſuperius ſpecificat' content' pro ipſo nuper Rege <hi>Edwardo</hi> Sexto &amp; Heredibus ſuis, Major. &amp; Communi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tat' ac Civibus Civit. <hi>London,</hi> &amp; Succeſſoribus ſuis Ratificavit et Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>firmavit, prout per eaſdem Litteras Patent' ejuſdem nuper Regis <hi>Edwar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>di</hi> Sexti inter alia plenius apparet. Quod<expan>
                     <am>
                        <g ref="char:abque"/>
                     </am>
                     <ex>que</ex>
                  </expan> Domina <hi>Maria</hi> nuper Regnii. <hi>Angl'</hi> per Litteras ſuas Patent' ſub
<pb facs="tcp:95897:12"/>magno ſigillo <hi>Angl.</hi> ſigillat. geren. dat. apud <hi>Weſtm.</hi> praedict. primo die <hi>Martii,</hi> Anno Regni ſui primo quas iidem Major &amp; Communitas ac Cives Civitat. <hi>London</hi> hic in Cur. proferunt pro ipſa nuper Regina He<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>red. &amp; Succeſſoribus ſuis omnes con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſſiones &amp; al. quaecun<expan>
                     <am>
                        <g ref="char:abque"/>
                     </am>
                     <ex>que</ex>
                  </expan> in praedict. litteris. patent. dicti Domin. Regis <hi>Johannis</hi> ſuperius ſpecificat. content. Majori et Communitat. ac Civibus Civitat. <hi>London</hi> praedict. et Succeſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſor. ſuis ratificavit et confirmavit prout per eaſdem litteras patent. ejuſdem nuper Regis int. al. plenius apparet. Quod<expan>
                     <am>
                        <g ref="char:abque"/>
                     </am>
                     <ex>que</ex>
                  </expan> Domina <hi>Elizabetha</hi> nuper Regin. <hi>Ang.</hi> per litteras ſuas patent. ſub magno ſigillo ſuo <hi>Angl.</hi> ſigillat. geren. dat. apud <hi>Weſtm.</hi> prae<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dict. nono die <hi>Maii,</hi> Anno Regni ſui quarto, quas iidem Major et Commu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nitas ac Cives Civitat. <hi>London</hi> hic in Cur. proferunt pro ipſa nuper Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gina <hi>Elizabetha</hi> Hered. et Succeſſori<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bus, ſuis omnes conceſſion. et al. quae<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cun<expan>
                     <am>
                        <g ref="char:abque"/>
                     </am>
                     <ex>que</ex>
                  </expan> in praedict. litteris patent. dicti Domin. Regis <hi>Johannis</hi> ſuperius ſpecificat. content. Majori et Commu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nitat. ac Civibus Civit. <hi>London</hi> et Succeſſoribus ſuis ratificavit et con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>firmavit, prout per eaſdem litteras patent. ejuſdem nuper Reginae <hi>Eliza<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>beth.</hi> inter alia plenius apparet. Et iidem Major et Communitas ac Cives Civitat. <hi>London</hi> ulterius dicunt, quod Domin. <hi>Jacobus</hi> nuper Rex <hi>Angl.</hi> per litteras ſuas patentes ſub magno ſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gillo ſuo <hi>Angl.</hi> ſigillat. geren. dat. a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pud Honorem ſuum de <hi>Hampton-Court</hi> Viceſimo quarto die <hi>Septembris</hi> Anno regni ſui <hi>Angl.</hi> ſexto quas ii<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dem Major et Communitas ac Cives Civitat. <hi>London</hi> hic in Cur. pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ferunt recitando, quod cum quamplu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rim. Progenitor. ipſius nuper Regis
<pb n="19" facs="tcp:95897:12"/>quondam Regis Angl. de gratia ſua ſpeciali ac pro gratis laudabil. mul<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tiplicibus &amp; continuis ſervitiis per Majorem &amp; Comunitat. ac Cives Ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vitat, <hi>London</hi> &amp; Praedeceſſores ſu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>os temporibus retractis fact. &amp; im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pens' necnon pro diverſas al. urgen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tibus cauſis &amp; conſiderationibus eos ſeperatim moventibus dediſſent con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſſiſſent &amp; confirmaſſent Majori &amp; Communitati ac Civibus Civitat. <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don</hi> praedict, ac Succeſſoribus ſuis di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verſis libertat. priviledg. Franc. imunitat. Authoritat. Juriſdiction. Ordinationes conſuetudin. &amp; quietan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tias prout per ſeperal. Litteras Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tent. Progenitor. &amp; Praedeceſſor. ſu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>or. quondum Regina Angl. plenius &amp; manefeſtus liquebat &amp; apparebat. Idem nuper Rex Jacobus pro &amp; in Conſideratione ſum. fidelitat. conſtant. prompt. &amp; laudabil. ſervitii per Majorem &amp; Comunitat. ac Cives Ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uitat. <hi>London</hi> praedict. eidem nuper Regi in in ipſis Regni ſui primis Auſpitii &amp; continue vſque tunc manifeſtat. &amp; fideliſſim. fact. &amp; impenſ. omnes &amp; ſingulas Litteras Patentes Cartas &amp; Confir<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mation. Praeclariſſimor. Progenitor. &amp; Anteceſſor. ſuor. eiſdem Majori &amp; Communitat. ac Civibus Civitat. <hi>London</hi> praedict. &amp; Praedeceſſoribus ſuis per quecun<expan>
                     <am>
                        <g ref="char:abque"/>
                     </am>
                     <ex>que</ex>
                  </expan> nomina incorporat. ante tunc tempora fact. conceſſ. ſeu confirmat. ac omnes &amp; ſingulas Do<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nationes Conceſſiones confirmation. reſtitution. Conſuetudines Ordinati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ones &amp; Explanationes Articul. &amp; omnes al. res quaſcun<expan>
                     <am>
                        <g ref="char:abque"/>
                     </am>
                     <ex>que</ex>
                  </expan> in quibuſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cun<expan>
                     <am>
                        <g ref="char:abque"/>
                     </am>
                     <ex>que</ex>
                  </expan> Litteris Patentibus ſine Char<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tis quorumcun<expan>
                     <am>
                        <g ref="char:abque"/>
                     </am>
                     <ex>que</ex>
                  </expan> Progenitor. Prede<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſſor. aut Anteceſſor. ſuor. Regum Angl. nec non omnia &amp; ſingula in dictis Litteris Patentibus Chartis Conceſſionibus Confirmationibus ſeu eor aliquibus content, recitat. ſpeci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ficat. confirmat. ſeu explanat. ac om<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nia &amp; ſingulis Juriſdictiones Autho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ritates Privilegia libertates &amp; Franches quietant. imunitates liberas
<pb facs="tcp:95897:13"/>conſuetudines &amp; Hereditament. que<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cun<expan>
                     <am>
                        <g ref="char:abque"/>
                     </am>
                     <ex>que</ex>
                  </expan> que praedict. Major &amp; Comu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nitat. ac Cives Civitat. <hi>London</hi> praedict. vel. Predeceſſor. ſui per nomen Majoris &amp; communitat. ac Ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vium Civitat. <hi>London</hi> ſeu per no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men Majoris &amp; Aldermann. Civitat. <hi>London</hi> ſeu per nomen Majoris Ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vium &amp; Comunitat. Civitat. <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don</hi> ſu per nomen Majoris &amp; Civi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>um Civitat. <hi>London</hi> ſeu per nomen Major. &amp; Comunitat. Civitat. <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don,</hi> ſeu per nomen Civium Civitat. <hi>London</hi> ſeu per nomen Baron <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don</hi> ſeu per nomen Baron Civitat. <hi>London</hi> ſeu per aliquod aliud no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men quodcun<expan>
                     <am>
                        <g ref="char:abque"/>
                     </am>
                     <ex>que</ex>
                  </expan> ratione ſeu Pigore ali<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quar. litterar. patent Chartar. ſeu con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>firmation. aliquor Progenitor. Prede<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſſor. aut Anteceſſor. ejuſdem nuper Regis <hi>Jacobi</hi> quondam Regium Angl. aliquo tempore vel aliquibus Tempo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ribus habuiſſent ſeu rationabilit. uſi fuiſſent aut exercuiſſent rata habuit &amp; grata ac pro ſe Heredibus &amp; Succeſſoribus ſuis acceptavit &amp; appro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bavit ac ea omnia &amp; ſingula praefat. Majori &amp; Communitat. ac Civibus Civitat. <hi>London</hi> praedict. &amp; eor' Succeſſoribus per eaſdem Litteras ſuas Patent. Ratificavit &amp; confirma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vit habend. &amp; tenend. gaudend. &amp; exercend. omnia &amp; ſingula praemiſſa eiſdem Majori &amp; Comunitat. ac Ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vibus Civitat. <hi>London</hi> praedict. &amp; Succeſſoribus ſuis imperpetuum adeo plene libere &amp; integre ac tam am<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plis modo &amp; forma &amp; ſi ſeperatim &amp; ſingulatim &amp; nominatim in Lit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teris Patentibus ill' expreſſmominat. declarat. recitat. &amp; manifeſtat. eſſent &amp; fuiſſent prout per eaſdem Litteras patentes inter alia plenius apparet Quod<expan>
                     <am>
                        <g ref="char:abque"/>
                     </am>
                     <ex>que</ex>
                  </expan> Domini <hi>Carolas</hi> Primus nu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>per Rex Angl. <hi>&amp;c.</hi> per Litteras ſuas patentes ſub magno ſigillo ſuo Angl. ſigillat. geren. dat apud <hi>Weſtm.</hi> praedict. decimo Octavo die Octobris Anno Regni ſui quartadecimo quas iidem Major &amp; Comunitas ac Cives
<pb n="20" facs="tcp:95897:13"/>Civitat. <hi>London</hi> hic in cur profe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>runt omnia &amp; ſingula privilegia li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bertat. Franch. quietant. immunita<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tes &amp; liberas Confuetudines quecunc<expan>
                     <am>
                        <g ref="char:abque"/>
                     </am>
                     <ex>que</ex>
                  </expan> que praedict. Major &amp; Comunitat. ac Cives Civitat. <hi>London</hi> praedict. vel Predeceſſor. ſui per nomen Mojoris &amp; Comunitas ac Civium Civitat. <hi>Lond.</hi> ſeu per nomen Majoris &amp; Alderman. Civium &amp; Comunitat. <hi>London</hi> ſeu per nomen Majoris &amp; Civium Civi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tat. <hi>London</hi> ſeu per nomen Majoris &amp; Communitatis <hi>London</hi> ſeu per no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men Civium Civitat. <hi>London</hi> ſeu per nomen Baron. <hi>London</hi> ſeu per nomen Baron. Civitat. <hi>London</hi> ſeu per ali<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quod aliud nomen quodcun<expan>
                     <am>
                        <g ref="char:abque"/>
                     </am>
                     <ex>que</ex>
                  </expan> ratione ſeu vigore praedict. litterar. patent. praedicti Domin. Regis <hi>Johnnis</hi> aut aliar. litterar. patent. Chartarum ſeu confirmation. in eiſdem litteris pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tentibus dicti nuper <hi>Regis Caroli</hi> primi mentioriat. vel uſu vel prae<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſcription. aut alio legali modo aliquo tempore vel aliquibus temporibus an<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>te tunc habuiſent ſeu rationabilit. uſi. fuiſcent aut exercuiſſent rata habem &amp; grata ea pro ſe Heredibus &amp; Succeſſoribus ſuis acceptavit &amp; approbavit ac ea omnia &amp; ſing<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ula praefat. Majori &amp; Commu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nitati ac Civibus Civitat. <hi>London</hi> &amp; eor. ſucceſſoribus per eaſdem lit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teras ſuas patentes ratificavit &amp; con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>firmavit prout per litteras patent il<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>las inter alia plenius apparet Quod<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>que praedictus Domini. Rex nunc per litteras ſuas patent. ſub magno ſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gillo ſuo Angl. ſigillat geren. dat. a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pud <hi>Weſtm.</hi> predict. viceſimo quarto die Junii Anno Regni ſui decimo quinto quas iidem Major &amp; Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>munitas ac Cives Civitat <hi>London</hi> hic in Cur. proferunt pro ipſo Rege Heredibus &amp; ſucceſtoribus ſuis rati ficavit &amp; confirmavit Majori &amp;
<pb facs="tcp:95897:14"/>Communitati ac Civibus, Civitat. <hi>London</hi> &amp; ſucceſſoribus ſuis omnia &amp; ſingula Juriſdiction. Authoritat. Privilegia libertates Eranch. qui<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>etant. immunitates &amp; conſuetudin. quecunquc que prefat. Major &amp; Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>munitas ac Cives Civitat. <hi>London</hi> vel Predeceſsores ſui per Nomen Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>joris &amp; Communitatis ac Civium Civitatis <hi>London</hi> ſeu per nomen Majoris Alldermannor. Civium &amp; Comunitat. <hi>London</hi> ſeu per Nomen Majoris &amp; Civium Civitatis <hi>London</hi> ſeu per nomen Major &amp; Communitat Civit <hi>London</hi> ſeu pes nomen Civi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>um Civitat <hi>London</hi> ſeu per. nomen Baron. <hi>London</hi> ſeu per nomen Ba<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ron. Civitat. <hi>London</hi> ſeu per aliquod aliud nomen quodcunque ratione vel vigore praedict. litterar patent prae<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dict. Domini Regis <hi>Johannis</hi> aut aliorum litterar patent Chartar ſeu conformation in eiſdem litteris pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tentibus dicti Domini Regis nunc praementionat vel alicujus ſeu ale<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quor uſus vel uſum praeſcription. vel praeſcription. ſeu alio legali modo quecunque aliquo tempore vel ali<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quibus temporibus antetunt ſeu ra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tionabilit. uſi fuiſſent aut exercuiſſent habend. tenend. gaudend. &amp; exertend. omnia &amp; ſingula praemiſſa praedict. eiſdem Majori &amp; Communitat. ac Ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vibus Civitat. <hi>London</hi> praedict. &amp; Succeſſoribus ſuis imperpetun. adeo plene libere &amp; integre ac in tam am<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plis modo &amp; forma prout, in eaſdem litteras patentibus ſuperius mentio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nant. fore data ſive conceſſa aut. alit uſu praeſciption vel aliolegalimodo ſeu jure quocunque ad tunc reſpective habit obtent. ſive gaviſa fuiſſent ac ei ſeperatim ſingulatim &amp; nominatim in &amp; per dictas litteras patentes ipſius Domini Regis nunc expreſs nominat. declarat. conceſſa &amp; ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nifeſta eſſent &amp; fuiſſent prout per eaſdem litteras patent. (inter alia) plenius apparet</p>
               <pb n="21" facs="tcp:95897:14"/>
               <p>Et iidem Major &amp; Communitas ac Cives Civitat' <hi>London</hi> ulterius dicunt quod a tempore confection' praedict' Litterar' Patent' praedict' quondam Regum <hi>Johannis</hi> hucuſ<expan>
                     <am>
                        <g ref="char:abque"/>
                     </am>
                     <ex>que</ex>
                  </expan> tidem Major &amp; Communitas ac Ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ves Civitat' <hi>London</hi> habuer' Vice<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>com' Civit' &amp; Com' Civit' <hi>London</hi> &amp; Vicecom' Comitat' <hi>Midd'</hi> &amp; quo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>libet anno nominaverunt &amp; elege<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>runt ex ſeipſis duas perſonas Cives Civitat' fore Vicecom' Civitat' prae<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dict' &amp; Com' ejuſdem Civitat' &amp; Vicecom' Com' <hi>Midd'</hi> ac ill' ſic no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mmat' &amp; elect' praeſecerunt &amp; con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>f<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>tuerunt Viccom' Civitat' praedict' &amp; Com' ejuſdem Civitat' &amp; Vice<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>com' Com' <hi>Midd'</hi> ac ut Vicecom' Ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vitat' praedict' &amp; Com' ejuſdem Ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vitat' ad execut' &amp; retorn' omniu' Breviu' Billar' &amp; Praeceptor' Domin' Begis pro adminiſtratione &amp; execu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tione Juſtitiae in infra Civit' prae<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dict' &amp; Com' ejuſdem Civitat' exe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quend' faciend' quae ad Officium Vicecom' faciend' pertinent' ac ad faciend' &amp; exequend' omnia &amp; ſin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gula alia infra Civitat' praedict' &amp; Com' ejuſdem Civitat' quae ad Offic' Vicecom' faciend' pertinent' ac ut Vicecom' <hi>Midd'</hi> pro eodem Com' de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſcrvitur ac omnia Brevia Billas &amp; Praeſcripta Domin' Regis infra Com' <hi>Midd'</hi> praedict' pro Adminiſtratione &amp; Executione Juſtitiae ibidem exe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quend' &amp; retorn' inde faciend' quae ad Officiu' Vicecom' faciend' perti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nent' Ft eo Warranto iidem Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jor &amp; Communitas ac Cives Civitat' <hi>London</hi> per tempus in Informatione praedicta ſuperius ſpecificat' uſi fuer' &amp; adhuc utunt' ac clamant habere &amp; uti libertat' Privilegia &amp; Franch' habere
<pb n="22" facs="tcp:95897:15"/>Vicecom' Civit' &amp; Com' Civit' <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don</hi> &amp; Vicecom' Comitat' <hi>Midd'</hi> &amp; nominare &amp; elegere ex ſeipſis duas perſon' fore Vicecom' Civitat' praedict' &amp; Com' ejuſdem Civit' &amp; Vicecom' <hi>Midd'</hi> ac ill' ac nominat' &amp; elect' praeficere &amp; conſtituere Vicecom' Civit' puaedict' &amp; Com' ejuſdem Civitat' &amp; Vicecom' <hi>Midd'</hi> ac ut Vicecom' Civitat' praedict' &amp; Com' ejuſdem Civitat' ad execut' &amp; retorn' omni' Litterar' Billar' &amp; Praeceptor' Domini Regis pro Adminiſtratione &amp; Executione Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtitiae infra Civitat' praedict' &amp; Com' ejuſdem Civit' exequend' fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ciend' quae ad Officiu' Vicecom' fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ciend' pertinent' ac ad faciend' &amp; exequend' omnia &amp; ſingula alia in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fra Civitat' praedict' &amp; Com' ejuſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dem Civitat' quae ad Offic' Vicecom' faciend' pertinent' ac ut Vicecom' <hi>Midd'</hi> pro eodem Com' deſervitur' ac omnia Brevia Billas &amp; Praecepta Domin' Reg' infra Com' <hi>Midd'</hi> prae<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dict' pro Adminiſtratione &amp; Exe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cutione Juſtitiae ibidem exequend' &amp; retorn' inde faciend' quae ad Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ficiu' Vicecom' faciend' pertinent' prout eis bene licuit &amp; licet.</p>
               <p>Abſque hoc quod idem Major &amp; Communit' ac Cives Civitat' <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don</hi> de Libertat' Privileg' &amp; Franch' ill' ſuper dictu' Dom' Regem nunc per tempus praedict' in Informatione praedicta ſuperius ſpecificat' uſurpa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver' &amp; uſurpant' pro ut per Inform' illam pro dicto Domin' Rege nunc ſuperius ſuppoſuit que omnia &amp; ſin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gula iidem Major' &amp; Communitat' ac Cives Civit' <hi>London</hi> parati ſunt verificare unde petit Judicium
<pb n="23" facs="tcp:95897:15"/>&amp; quod Libertat' Privileg' &amp; Franch' ill' eis &amp; Succeſſoribus ſuis in perpetuu' deinceps allocent' &amp; ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>judicentur ac quod ipſi quoad Prae<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſa ill' ab hac' Cur' dimittantur, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>Et iidem Major &amp; Communitas &amp; Cives Civit' <hi>London</hi> quoad Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bertat' Privileg' &amp; Franch' ſequen' viz. Major dictae Civitat' pro hu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>juſmodi Aldermann' ejuſdem Civit' qui Officiu' Majoris Civit' illius ſu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſi inner' ac inde fuer' dimiſſi ac tres Senior' Aldermann' Civit' praedict' qui diutius in Officiu' Aldermanat' Civit' praedict' ſteter' &amp; onus &amp; Officiu' Majorat' Civit' praedict' non ſuſtinner' fore Juſtic' Dom' Regis ad Pacem infra Civitat' praedict' con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſervand' ac ad Seſſion' Pacis &amp; Pla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cita Coron' ſcilicet talia Placit' Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ronae qual' Juſtic' Domin' Regis ad Pacem Conſervand' Aſſign' ligittim' tenere poſſent inf' eandem Civit' te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nend' ac ad omnes Felon' Riot' Rout' &amp; Conventicul' illicit' infra Civit' praedict' inquirend' audiend' &amp; ter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>minand' in Informatione praedict' ſu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>perius ſpecificat' dic' quod dict' Do<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>min' Rex nunc ipſos Majorem &amp; Communitat' ac Cives Civitat' <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don</hi> occaſione inde impetere ſeu oc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>caſionare non debet quia dicunt quod praedict' Civit' <hi>London</hi> eſt &amp; a tempore cujus contrar' memor' homin' non exiſtit fuit antiqua Civitas ac antiquus Comitat' de ſe ac Cives ejuſdem Civit' ſunt &amp; a praedicto tempore cujus contrar' memor' homin' non exiſtit ſuer' <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>nu' Corpus corpo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rat' &amp; Politic' in re facto &amp; no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mine per nomen Majoris &amp; Commu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nitat' ac Cives Civitat' <hi>London.</hi> Quodque Domin' <hi>Carolus</hi> Primus nuper Rex <hi>Angl'</hi> per Litteras ſuas Patent' ſub Magno Sigillo ſuo <hi>Angl'</hi> Sigillat geren' dat' apud <hi>Weſtm'</hi> praedict' Decimo octavo die <hi>Octo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bris</hi>
                  <pb n="24" facs="tcp:95897:16"/>Anno Regni ſui quarto decimo quas iidem Major &amp; Communitas ac Cives Civit' <hi>London</hi> hic in Cur' proferunt pro ipſo nuper Rege He<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>red' &amp; Succeſſorib' ſuis conceſſit Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jori &amp; Communitat' ac Civibus Ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vit' <hi>London</hi> &amp; eoru' Succeſſoribus quod Major &amp; Recordat' Civit' prae<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dict' qui tunc fuer' ac Majores &amp; Recordator' Civit' praedict' qui pro tempore fuerent ac tam ill' Aldermann' qui Major' Civitat' illius praeantea extitiſſent quam ill' Aldermann' qui onus &amp; Officiu' Majorat' Civitat' praedict' tunc in poſteru' ſuſtinnerent &amp; gererent licet a Majorat' ill' ceſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſerent aut inde eſſent dimiſſi qui<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dam Aldermann' ibidem ſtarent &amp; tres Seniores Aldermann' Civit' praedict' per tempus exiſten' qui diu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tius in Officiu' Aldermannat' ſteter' &amp; ante tunc onus &amp; Officiu' Majo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rat' Civitat' illius non ſuſtinuer' im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>perpetuu' forent Cuſtodes &amp; quidli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bet eor' eſſet Cuſtos Pacis ejuſdem nuper Regis Hered' &amp; Succeſſor' inf' Civitat' <hi>London</hi> praedict' &amp; Libertat' ejuſdem conſervand' &amp; cu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtodiend' ac eoſdem Majorem &amp; Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cordator' ac Aldermann' praedict' ac omnia &amp; ſingula Statuta &amp; Ordi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nationes pro bono Pacis dicti nuper Regis Hered' &amp; Succeſſorib' ſuor' ac pro conſervatione ejuſdem ac pro quiet' Regimine &amp; Gubernatione Po<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>puli ipſius nuper Regis Hered' &amp; Succeſſor' ſuor' edit' &amp; edend' &amp; omnib' ſuis Articul' tam infra Ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vitat' praedict' quam Libertat' ejuſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dem juxta vim formam &amp; effectu' eorundem Cuſtodiend' &amp; cuſtodire faciend' ac ad omnes illos quos juxta forma' &amp; effectu' Ordination' &amp; Sta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tutar' eorundem &amp; eoru' alicujus in Civitat' praedict' pro Libertat' ejuſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dem Delinquentes invenirent caſti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gand' &amp; puniend'prout ſecundu' forma'
<pb n="25" facs="tcp:95897:16"/>Ordination' &amp; Statutor' ill' foret faciend' Et ad omnes illos qui ali<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cui vel aliquibus de Populo ejuſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dem nuper Regis Haered' vel Suc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſſor' ſuor' de Corporationibus ſuis vol de incendio Dombr' ſuar' minas facerent ad ſufficien' ſecuritat' de Pace vel Bono geſtu ſuo erga ipſu' nuper Regem Haered' &amp; Succeſſores ſuos &amp; cunctis Populis ejus Haered' vel Succeſſor' invenirend' Et ſi hu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>juſmodi ſecuritat' ivenire recuſarent tunc eos in Gaola ejuſdem Domin' Regis de <hi>Newgate</hi> vel in aliqua al' Priſona Haered' vel Succeſſor' ſuor' in praedict' Civit' <hi>London</hi> quouſ<expan>
                     <am>
                        <g ref="char:abque"/>
                     </am>
                     <ex>que</ex>
                  </expan> bujuſmodi ſecuritat' inveni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rent ſalvo cuſtodiri faciend' Cuſtodes &amp; Juſtitiar' ipſius nuper Regis &amp; quemlibet coru' &amp; Cuſtodem &amp; Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtitiar' ejus Hered' &amp; Succeſſor' ſuor' infra Civit' <hi>London</hi> praedict' &amp; Libertat' ejuſdem idem nuper Rex <hi>Carolus</hi> Primus pro<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ſe Here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dibus &amp; Succeſſoribus ſuis conſtituit fecit &amp; Ordinavit per Litteras Patentes ſuas praedict' ac ad omnin &amp; ſingula alia exequend' &amp; pera<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gend' quae Juſtic' &amp; Cuſtod' Pacis ejus Hered' vel Succeſſor' ſuor' inf' aliquum Com' Regni ſui <hi>Angl'</hi> exe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>qui ſive peragere valerent poſſent aut deberent virtute aliquor' Sta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tutor' &amp; Ordination' hujus Begni ſui <hi>Angl'</hi> aut vertute Commiſſionis ejus Hered' &amp; Succeſſor' ſuor' ad Pacem in aliquo hujuſmodi Com' conſervand' voluit etiam idem nuper Rex <hi>Carolus</hi> Primus ac per eaſdem Litteras Patentes pro ſe Heredi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bus &amp; Succeſſoribus ſuis conceſſit praefat' Majori &amp; Communitati ac de Civibus Civitat' <hi>London</hi> &amp; eoru' Succeſſor' quod Major &amp; Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cordator' Civit' praedict' pro tem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pore exiſten' &amp; hujuſmodi ut pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fert' Aldermann' pro tempore exi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſten' qui Officiu' vel locu' Majorat'
<pb n="26" facs="tcp:95897:17"/>Civit' illius antea ſuſtinner' &amp; ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ercuer' &amp; tres hujuſmodi ut prae<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fert' Seniores Aldermann' pro tem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pore exiſten' qui locu' Majorat' prae<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dict' non ſuſtinner' vel quatuor eo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rundem Major' Recordator' &amp; Al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dermannorum quoru' dict' Major &amp; Recordator' pro tempore exiſten' unu' eſſe voluit forent Juſticiar' ipſius nu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>per Regis Hered' &amp; Succeſſor' ſuor' &amp; ipſos Juſticiar' ſuos Hered' &amp; Succeſſor' ſuor' pro ſe Heredibus &amp; Succeſſor' ſuis imperpetuu' aſſignavit ad inquirend' quotiens &amp; quando eis melius videret' expedire per Sacra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mentu' probor' &amp; legalu' homin' tam de Civitat' praedict' quam de Liber<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tat' ejuſdem per quos rei veritas melius ſciri poſſet de omnibus Mur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dris Felon' Veneficiis Incantation' Scortileg' Arte Magicie Tranſgr' Foreſtallar' Regretar' Ingroſſar' &amp; Extortionibus quibuſcunque ac de omnibus &amp; ſingulis al' Malefactis &amp; Offens' de quibus Juſticiar' Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cis ipſius nuper Regis Hered' &amp; Succeſſor' ſuor' legitime inquirere poſſent aut deberent per quoſcun<expan>
                     <am>
                        <g ref="char:abque"/>
                     </am>
                     <ex>que</ex>
                  </expan> &amp; qualitercun<expan>
                     <am>
                        <g ref="char:abque"/>
                     </am>
                     <ex>que</ex>
                  </expan> infra Civit' praed' ſeu Libertat' ejuſdem antetunc habit' ſeu perpetrat' vel quae extunc ibi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dem fieri vel attemptari continge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rent &amp; tam de omnibus ill' qui in Civitat' praedict' &amp; Libertat' ejuſd' in Conventiculis contra Pacem ipſius nuper Regis Hered' &amp; Succeſſor' ſu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>or' in perturbatione Populi ſui He<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>red' &amp; Succeſſor' ſuor' ſeu vi arma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ta irent vel equitarent ſeu extunc ire vel equitare preſumerent. Et etiam de hiis quae ibidem ad gen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tem dict' Dom' Regis Hered' vel Succeſſor' ſuor' machin' vel interfici<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>end' in Incidiis jacerent vel impoſte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ru' jacere praeſumerent. Ac etiam de
<pb n="27" facs="tcp:95897:17"/>Hoſtillar' &amp; al' omnibus &amp; ſingulis perſon' qui in abuſu menſurar' &amp; ponderu' ſive in venditione Victual' contra formam Ordination' &amp; Sta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tut' vel eoru' alicujus inde Commu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ni <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>tilitate Regni ſui <hi>Angl'</hi> &amp; Populi ejuſdem nuper Regis Hered' &amp; Succeſſor' ſuor' ejuſdem edit' &amp; edend' delinquerent vel attempterent &amp; in Civit' praedict' &amp; Libertat' ejuſdem ſeu extunc impoſteru' delin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quere vel attemptare preſumerent. Ac etiam de quibuſcun<expan>
                     <am>
                        <g ref="char:abque"/>
                     </am>
                     <ex>que</ex>
                  </expan> Vicecom' Conſtabular' Cuſtod' Gaole &amp; al' Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fic' qui non execut' Officiu' ſuor' cir<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ca premiſſor' vel eor' aliqua indebere ſe habuer' aut impoſteru' indebere ſe habuere preſumerent aut tepidi pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſs' vel negligentes fuer' aut ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tunc tepidi premiſs' vel negligent' fore contingerent infra Civit' praed' &amp; Libertat' ejuſdem ac de omnibus &amp; ſingulis Articulis &amp; Circumſtant' &amp; al' quibuſcun<expan>
                     <am>
                        <g ref="char:abque"/>
                     </am>
                     <ex>que</ex>
                  </expan> per quoſcun<expan>
                     <am>
                        <g ref="char:abque"/>
                     </am>
                     <ex>que</ex>
                  </expan> &amp; qualitercun<expan>
                     <am>
                        <g ref="char:abque"/>
                     </am>
                     <ex>que</ex>
                  </expan> in Civit' praed' &amp; Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bertat' ejuſdem fact' ſive perpetrat' &amp; quae extunc ibidem fieri vel at<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>temptarit contingerent qualitercun<expan>
                     <am>
                        <g ref="char:abque"/>
                     </am>
                     <ex>que</ex>
                  </expan> prewiſs' aut eor' aliqua concernen' Et ad Indictament' quecun<expan>
                     <am>
                        <g ref="char:abque"/>
                     </am>
                     <ex>que</ex>
                  </expan> quae co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ram Majore aut Recordatore Civit' praedict' pro tempore exiſten' &amp; hu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>juſmodi ut prefert' Aldermann' vel quatuor aut pluribus eorundem quor' dict' Major vel Recordator' pro tem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pore exiſten' unu' eſſe voluit tunc impoſteru' caperent' inſpiciend' &amp; ad proceſs' inde pres' omnes &amp; ſing<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap>, ſic indictat' vel quos im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſteru' ac indictat' contingerent quouſque caperent' redderent ſe vel
<pb n="28" facs="tcp:95897:18"/>utlagarent' faciend' &amp; continuand' &amp; ad omnia &amp; ſingula murdra fellon' veneſic' incantat' ſcortileg' Artis magic' tam falſas Conſpira<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion' &amp; al' malefact' foreſtall' re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>grat' ingroſſar' Extortion' Conven<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ticul' Indictament' pred' ceteraque omnia &amp; ſingula premiſs' ſecund' Leges &amp; Statut' Regni ſui <hi>Angl'</hi> prout in hujuſmodi Caſu fieri con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſuevit aut debuit audiend' &amp; ter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>minand' &amp; ad caſdem delinquen' &amp; quamlibet eoru' pro debit' ſuis per fines redemption' amerciament' forisfactur' &amp; al' modo prout ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cundum Legem &amp; Conſuetud' Regni ſui <hi>Angl'</hi> ac formam Ordination' &amp; Statut' corundem fieri conſuevit aut debuit caſtigand' &amp; puniend' ac ad omnia al' &amp; ſingula faciend' exer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cend' audiend' terminand' &amp; exe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quend' infra Civit' praed' ac Liber<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tat' ejuſdem quae Juſtic' ad pacem per Leges vel per Statut' hujus Regni ſui <hi>Angl'</hi> facere exercere in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quirere vel exequi poſſent &amp; vale<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rent &amp; in tam amplis' modo &amp; for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ma prout aliquis' al' aut aliqui al' Juſtic' ad Pacem in aliquibus al' Com' hujus' regni ſui <hi>Angel'</hi> ligit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>time facere exercere inquirere pu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nire vel quoque modo exequi poſſent aut valerent' prout per eaſdem Lit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teras Patent' inter al' plenius ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>paret Quodque predictus Domin' Rex nunc per Litteras ſuas Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tent' ſub Magno Sigillo ſuo <hi>Angl'</hi> Sigillat' geren' dat' apud <hi>Weſtm'</hi> predict' viceſimo quarto die Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nii Anno Regni ſui decimo quinto quas iidem Major &amp; Communitas ac Cives Civit' <hi>London</hi> hic
<pb facs="tcp:95897:18"/>in Cur' proferunt omnes Conceſſion' &amp; al' quecunque in predict' Litteris Patent' predict' nuper Regis <hi>Caroli</hi> Primi Superius ſpecificat' pro eodem Domin' Regis nunc Hered' &amp; Suc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſſor' ſuis Majori &amp; Communitat' ac Civibus Civit' <hi>London</hi> pred' &amp; coru' Succeſſor' in perpetuu' ratifica<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vit &amp; confirmavit prout per eaſdem Litteras Patent' ipſius Domin' Regis nunc inter al' plenius apparet &amp; iidem Major &amp; Communitas ac Ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ves Civit' <hi>London</hi> Ulterius dicunt quod tempore confection' predict' Lit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>terar' Patent' pred' nuper Regis <hi>Caroli</hi> Primi &amp; dum antea &amp; extunc hucuſque fuer' &amp; adhuc ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>iſtunt Major' &amp; Recordator' Civit' pred' ac Alderman' ejuſdem Civit'. qui Major dicte Civit' extitiſſent &amp; onus Majorat' Civit' illius ſuſtin' ac tres &amp; plures! Alderman' ejuſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dem Civit' qui onus Majorat' Civit' ill' non ſuſtinuiſſent Quodque a tem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pore confection' eorundem Litterar' Patent' predict' nuper Regis <hi>Caroli</hi> Primi hucuſque Major &amp; Recordator Civit' pred' pro tempore exiſtend ac hujuſmodi Alderman' ejuſdem Ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vitat' pro tempore exiſten' qui onus Majorat' Civit' ill' ſuſtin' Necnon tres Senior' Alderman' Civit' pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dict' pro tempore exiſten' qui diuti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>us in Officiu' Aldermannat' Civit' pred' ſteter', &amp; onus &amp; Officit' Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jorat' Civit' ill' non ſuſtin' virtute Litterar' Patent' ill' fuer' Juſtic' ad pacem infra Civit' pred' &amp; libertat' ejuſdem conſervand' ac virtute Lit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>terar' Patent' ill' &amp; ſecundum for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mam &amp; effectu' eorund' de tempore in tempus per tot' tempus ill' tener' Seſſion' pacis &amp; placita coron' ſci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>licet talia placita coron' qual' Juſtic' Domin' Regis ad pacem conſervand'
<pb n="30" facs="tcp:95897:19"/>aſſign' per idem tempus ligittime te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner' vel tenere potueri inf' eandem Civitat'.</p>
               <p>Et eo Warranto iidem Major &amp; Communitas ac Cives Civit' <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don</hi> per tempus in Informatione praed' ſuperius ſpecificat' uſi fuer' &amp; adhuc utuntur ac clamant habere &amp; uti Libertat' Privileg' &amp; Franch' quod Major dict' Civit' &amp; hujuſmo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>di Aldermann' ejuſdem Civit' qui onus Majorat' Civit' ill' ſuſtinner' ac inde fuerunt dimiſſi ac tres ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niores Aldermann' ejuſdem Civit' qui diutius Offic' Aldermannat' Ci, vit praedict' ſteter' &amp; onus &amp; Offi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ciu' Majorat' Civit' ill' non ſuſtu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ler' fuer' Juſtic' Domin' Regis ad Pacem infra Civit' praedict' conſer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vand' ac ad Seſſion' Pacis &amp; Pla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cita Corone (ſcilicet) talia Placita Coron' qual' Juſtic' Domin' Regis ad Pacem conſervand' aſſign' ligit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>time tenere poſſent infra eand' Ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vit' tenend' ac ad omnes Felon' Riot' Rout' &amp; Conventicul' illicit' infra Civit' praed' inquirend' audi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>end' &amp; terminand' prout eis bene licuit &amp; licet.</p>
               <p>Abſque hoc quod idem Major &amp; Communitas ac Cives Civit' <hi>London</hi> de Libertat' Privileg' &amp; Franches ill' ſuper dictum Domin' Regem nunc per tempus praed' in Informatione praed' ſuperius ſpecificat' uſurpaver' ſeu uſurpant pro ut per Inform' illam pro dicto Dom' Rege nunc ſuperius ſupponit' Quae omn' &amp; ſingula iidem Major &amp; Communitas &amp; Cives Ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vit' <hi>London</hi> perati ſunt verificare unde petunt Judicium &amp; quod Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bertat' Privileg' &amp; Franch' illis eis &amp; Succeſſoribus ſuis in perpetuum deinceps allocentur &amp; adjudicent' ac
<pb n="31" facs="tcp:95897:19"/>quod ipſi quoad premiſſa illi ab hac Curia dimittantur, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>Et quoad reſid' Libertat' Privi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>leg' &amp; Franchiſa in Information' praedict' ſpecificat' per iſum Majorem &amp; Communitat' ac Cives Civitat' <hi>London</hi> ſuperimo nomine clamat iidem Major &amp; Communit' ac Cives Civit' <hi>London</hi> Libertat' Privileg' &amp; Franchiſa illis nunquam uſi fue<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>runt ſeu utuntur ſed de eiſdem pe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nitus declamans, &amp;c.</p>
            </div>
            <div xml:lang="eng" type="version">
               <pb n="3" facs="tcp:95897:3"/>
               <head>The Mayor Commonalty and Citizens of <hi>London</hi> at the Suit of the King.</head>
               <p>ANd the ſaid Mayor and Commonalty and Citi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>zens of the City of <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don,</hi> by <hi>Bendict Brown</hi> their Attor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney, came and had Hearing of the Information aforeſaid, by colour of which Information they are Proſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cuted and may be hereafter burthen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed vexed and diſquieted, and that unjuſtly, becauſe by Proteſtation that in the ſaid Information there is no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thing contain'd material or ſufficient in the Law, to which Information they have no neceſſity, nor by the Law of the Land they ought to be held in any manner to Anſwer ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vertheleſs for Plea; for as much as the Liberties, Priviledges and Fran<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chizes following, <hi>viz.</hi> They the ſaid Mayor and Commonalty and Citi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>zens of the City of <hi>London</hi> to be of themſelves one Body Corporate and Politick in matter fact and name, by the Name of Mayor and Commo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nalty and Citizens of the City of <hi>London,</hi> and by that Name to Plead and be Impleaded, to Anſwer, and be Anſwered in the Information above ſpecified, the ſaid Mayor Comonal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty and Citizens of the City of <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don</hi> ſay, That our ſaid Soveraign Lord the King that now is, ought not by occaſion thereof to Impeach or undoe them, becauſe he ſaith, That the ſaid City of <hi>London</hi> is, and from which time beyond the memo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry of Man was an Ancient City; and that the Citizens of the ſaid Ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty are, and from that time out of
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:95897:4"/>mind were one Body Corporate and Politick in Matter, Fact, and Name, by the name of Mayor and Commo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nalty and Citizens of the City of <hi>London,</hi> and by that Name during that time have Pleaded, and were Impleaded; have Anſwered, and were Anſwered, and to Plead and be Impleaded, to Anſwer and be An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſwered, and during the time afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid have been uſed and accuſtomed. And that in the Great Charter of the Liberties of <hi>England</hi> in the Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment of our Soveraign Lord <hi>Henry</hi> the Third ſometime King of <hi>Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land,</hi> at <hi>Weſtminſter</hi> in the County of <hi>Middleſex,</hi> in the Ninth Year of his Reign, held, made and provided it is contained, That the Citizens of <hi>London</hi> ſhould have all their ancient Liberties and Cuſtoms; And the ſaid Mayor and Commonalty &amp; Ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tizens of the City of <hi>London</hi> further ſay, That the Lord <hi>Edward</hi> the Third ſometimes King of <hi>England,</hi> in his Parliament at <hi>Weſtminſter</hi> in the County of <hi>Middleſex,</hi> in the Firſt Year of his Reign held, by which his Charter, with the conſent of the Prelates, Earls Barons and the whole Commonalty of his Realm in his ſaid Parliament at <hi>Weſtminſter</hi> aforeſaid were Aſſembled. And by the Authority of the ſaid Parliament was then Confirmed to the Citizens of the City of <hi>London</hi> aforeſaid, the Liberties following (amongſt other things) to hold to themſelves and their Succeſſors for Ever, firſt of all in reciting: That whereas in the Great Charter of the Liberties of <hi>England</hi> it is contained, That the City of <hi>London</hi> ſhould have all their ancient Liberties and Cu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtoms; And that the ſaid Citizens, at the time of making the ſaid Char<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter, and in the times of King <hi>Ed<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ward</hi> the Confeſſor, and of <hi>William</hi> the Conquerour and other Progeni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tors of the ſaid King <hi>Edward</hi> in di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verſe
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:95897:4"/>Liberties and Cuſtoms have had not only by the Charters of their Progenitors, but alſo of other Charters of ancient cuſtom, the ſaid King <hi>Edward</hi> the Third did give and grant for himſelf and his Heirs by thoſe Charters, by the Authority aforeſaid, that the ſaid Citizens ſhall have their Liberties according to the form of the Great Charter aforeſaid; And that for any perſo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nal Tranſgreſſion or perſonal Judg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment of any Officer of the ſaid City, the Liberty of that City ſhall not be taken into the hands of King <hi>Ed<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ward</hi> the Third or his Succeſſors, but ſuch Officer for ſuch Offence ſhall be required and puniſhed, as by the ſaid Charter, bearing date at <hi>Weſtminſter</hi> aforeſaid, the ſixth day of <hi>March,</hi> in the firſt Year of the Reign of the ſaid King <hi>Edward</hi> the Firſt under his Great Seal of <hi>Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land,</hi> brought here in Court, among other things more fully doth ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pear. And the ſaid Mayor, Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>monalty and Citizens of the City of <hi>London</hi> further ſay, That at the inſtance (and at the requeſt of the Commonalty of the Realm of <hi>Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land</hi>) in the Parliament of our ſaid Lord <hi>Richard</hi> the Second, late King of <hi>England,</hi> after the Conqueſt, at <hi>Weſtminſter</hi> aforeſaid, in the ſeventh Year of his Reign, held and aſſem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bled for the greater quiet and peace among the Subjects of the late King, and for the publick good, all Cu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtoms, Liberties, Priviledges, and Franchiſes of the ſaid City then to the Citizens of that City and their Succeſſors, although they have not been uſed or abuſed, have been rati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fied and confirmed by the Authority of the ſaid Parliament. And that our Lord <hi>Henry</hi> the Sixth, late King of <hi>England,</hi> by his Letters Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tents, ſealed with his Great Seal of <hi>England,</hi> bearing date at <hi>Weſtmin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſter</hi> aforeſaid, the ſixth day of
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:95897:5"/>
                  <hi>October,</hi> in the Twenty third Year of his Reign, which the ſaid May<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>or, Commonalty and Citizens of the City of <hi>London</hi> brings here in Court for their Heirs and Succeſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſors, did confirm to the Mayor and Commonalty, and to the Ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tizens of the City of <hi>London</hi> and their Succeſſors, all and ſingular their Liberties, Franchizes, and free Cuſtoms, ſo whole and un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>touched in any time of the Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>genitors of the late King <hi>Henry</hi> the Sixth, when as more free<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly and better they had the ſame, as by the ſaid Letters Patents, a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mong other things more fully ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pears. And that our Lord <hi>Edward</hi> the Fourth, late King of <hi>England,</hi> by his Letters Patents, under his Great Seal of <hi>England,</hi> bearing date at <hi>Weſtminſter</hi> aforeſaid, the Ninth day of <hi>November,</hi> in the Second Year of his Reign, which the ſaid Mayor and Commonalty and Ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tizens of the City of <hi>London</hi> brings here in Court, for themſelves and their Heirs, did confirm to the Mayor and Commonalty and to the Citizens of the City of <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don</hi> and their Succeſſors for ever, all and ſingular their Liberties, Franchizes and free Cuſtoms, ſo whole and untouched, like as to them in any time of the Progeni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tors of the ſaid late King <hi>Edward</hi> the Fourth, they have had and held more quiet and free. And further, the ſaid late King <hi>Edward</hi> the Fourth, by his Letters Patents, did grant to the ſaid Mayor and Commonalty and to the Citizens, that although they or their Prede<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſſors, or the Mayor and Alder<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men of the ſaid City or their Pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>deceſſors before or ſucceeding then from thence after any or to any Liberties, did quietly grant the Order of Articles or free Cuſtoms, or of any other in the ſaid Letters
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:95897:5"/>Patents of the ſaid late King <hi>Edward</hi> the Fourth, or other his Letters Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tents contained, or of his Progeni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tors ſometime Kings of <hi>England</hi> to the Mayor and Commonalty, did grant in any Caſe ariſing, albeit, they have not been fully uſed or abuſed: Notwithſtanding the ſaid King <hi>Edward</hi> the Fourth was unwil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling that for this, they the Mayor and Commonalty Aldermen, and Citi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>zens, or their Succeſſors ſhould in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cur the forfeiture of the Premiſes; but that they and their Succeſſors all and ſingular the Liberties, Free<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>doms, Grants, Ordinations in the Articles, free-Cuſtoms, and what<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſoever elſe in the Charters and Let<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ters aforeſaid contained the like not uſed, or alſo abuſed, and every of them from thence of the reſt fully and freely may uſe and enjoy with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out the Impeachment or Impediment of the ſaid late King, or his Heirs of the Juſtices, Eſcheators, Sheriffs any other Bayliff or Officer of the ſaid late King, or any other whatſoever, as by the ſaid Letters Patents of the ſaid late King <hi>Edward</hi> the Fourth, brought here in Court; among other things more fully appeared. And that the late King <hi>Henry</hi> the Seventh by his Letters Patents un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der his Great Seal of <hi>England</hi> bear<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing Date at <hi>Weſtminſter</hi> aforeſaid, the 23<hi>d.</hi> Day of <hi>July,</hi> in the 20th. Year of his Reign, which the ſaid Mayor and Commonalty and Citi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>zens of the City of <hi>London</hi> brings here in Court for themſelves their Heirs and Succeſſors did ratifie and confirm to the Mayor and Commo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nalty and Citizens of the City of <hi>London</hi> and their Succeſſors all and ſingular the Liberties, Priviledges, Freedoms and Free Cuſtoms, which they the ſaid Mayor, Commonalty and Citizens, or their Predeceſſors have been accuſtomed to have, ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>erciſe or enjoy, or have been uſed or
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:95897:6"/>accuſtomed ſo fully, plainly, and wholly, as if all and ſingular the ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veral words in the ſaid Letters Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tents were and have been expreſſed, declared, and manifeſted, as by the ſaid Letters Patents among other things more fully appears. And the ſaid Mayor and Commonalty and Citizens of the City of <hi>London</hi> fur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther ſays, That the late King <hi>James</hi> by his Letters Patents under his Great Seal of <hi>England,</hi> bearing Date at his Honour of <hi>Hampton-Court</hi> the 24th. day of <hi>September</hi> in the 6th. Year of his Reign which the ſaid Mayor and Commonalty and Citi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>zens of the City of <hi>London</hi> brings here in Court by reciting that whereas many others of his Pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>deceſſors ſometime Kings of <hi>England</hi> of his ſpecial Grace for the many acceptable, laudable, and continued Services by the Mayor and Commo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nalty and Citizens of the City of <hi>London</hi> and their Predeceſſors in times paſt done, and unrewarded; alſo for divers other urgent Cau<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſes and conſiderations, them ſeverally moving did give grant and confirm to the Mayor and Commonalty and to the Citizens of the City of <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don</hi> and their Succeſſors divers Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>berties Priviledges, Franchizes, Im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>munities, Authorities, Juriſdictions, Ordinances, Cuſtoms and Freedoms; as by the ſeveral Letters Patents of the Progenitors and Predeceſſors of the ſaid late Kings of <hi>England</hi> more fully and manifeſt it doth, and may appear. The ſaid King <hi>James</hi> for, and in conſideration of the great Fideli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty, Conſtancy, and very late and laudable Service by the Mayor and Commonalty and Citizens of the City of <hi>London</hi> aforeſaid, to the late King of this Realm in his firſt com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing to this Realm, and continuing until then manifeſted and moſt faith<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fully done and unrewarded all and ſingular Letters Patents Charters,
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:95897:6"/>and Confirmations of his moſt noble Progenitors and Predeceſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſors to the ſaid Mayor and Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>monalty and Citizens of the City of <hi>London</hi> aforeſaid and their Suc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſſors, by what name ſoever in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>corporated, before that time made, granted or confirmed, and all and ſingular Donations, Grants, Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>firmations, Reſtitutions, Cuſtoms, Ordinances, Explanations, Articles, and all other things whatſoever in whatſoever Letters Patents or Char<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ters whatſoever of the Progenitors, Predeceſſors or Anceſtors of the ſaid Kings of <hi>England;</hi> alſo all and ſin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gular in the ſaid Letters Patents, Charters, Conceſſions, Confirma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions, or any of them contained, recited, ſpecified, confirmed, or explained. And all and ſingular Juriſdictions, Authorities, Privi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ledges, Liberties, Franchizes, Free<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>doms, Immunities, free Cuſtoms, and Hereditaments whatſoever, which the Mayor and Commonal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty and Citizens of the City of <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don</hi> or their Predeceſſors, by the Name of the Mayor and Common<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>alty and of the Citizens of the City of <hi>London,</hi> or by the Name of the Mayor and Aldermen of the City of <hi>London,</hi> or by the Name of the Mayor, Citizens and Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>monalty of the City of <hi>London</hi> or by the Name of Mayor and Citi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>zens of the City of <hi>London,</hi> or by the Name of the Mayor and Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>monalty of the City of <hi>London,</hi> or by the Name of the Citizens of the City of <hi>London,</hi> or by the Name of Barons of <hi>London,</hi> or by the Name of Barons of the City of <hi>London,</hi> or by any other Name whatſoever, by reaſon or force of any Letters Patents, Charters or Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſirmations of any the Progenitors, Predeceſſors or Anceſtors of the ſaid late King <hi>James,</hi> in any time or times have been had or reaſonably
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:95897:7"/>been uſed or exerciſed, or have been adjudged for themſelves and their Heirs and Succeſſors, did accept and approve, and all and ſingular to the ſaid Mayor and Commonalty and to the Citizens of the City of <hi>London</hi> aforeſaid, and their Succeſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſors, by the ſaid Letters Patents did ratifie and confirm to have, hold, enjoy, and exerciſe, all and ſingular the Premiſſes to the ſaid Mayor and Commonalty and to the Citizens of the City of <hi>London</hi> aforeſaid, and their Succeſſors for ever, ſo fully, freely, and wholly, as in as large manner and form as if every ſeveral ſingle Name, and Name by Name, in thoſe ſaid Let<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ters Patents have been expreſſed, named, declared, recited, and ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nifeſted, as by the ſaid Letters Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tents, among other things, more fully appears. And that the ſaid late King <hi>Charles</hi> the Firſt by his Letters Patents, under his Great Seal of <hi>England,</hi> bearing date at <hi>Weſt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>minſter</hi> aforeſaid, the Eighteenth day of <hi>October,</hi> in the Fourteenth Year of his Reign, which the ſaid Mayor and Commonalty and Ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tizens of the City of <hi>London</hi> brings here in Court, all and ſingular Pri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viledges, Liberties, Franchizes, Freedoms, Immunities and free Cuſtoms whatſoever, which the ſaid Mayor and Commonalty and Citizens of the City of <hi>London</hi> a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid, or their Predeceſſors, by the Name of the Mayor and Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>monalty and Citizens of the City of <hi>London,</hi> or by the Name of the Mayor and Aldermen, Citizens and Commonalty of <hi>London,</hi> or by the Name of Mayor and Citizens of the City of <hi>London,</hi> or by the Name of Mayor and Commonal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty of the City of <hi>London,</hi> or by the Name of the Citizens of the City of <hi>London,</hi> or by the Name of the Barons of <hi>London,</hi> or by the Name
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:95897:7"/>of the Barons of the City of <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don,</hi> or by any other Name whatſoever, by reaſon or force of the ſaid Letters Patents, Charters or Confirmations in the ſaid Let<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ters Patents of the ſaid late King <hi>Charles</hi> the Firſt mentioned, or in uſe or by preſcription, or in any o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther lawful manner, in any time or in any time or times before that time have had or have been reaſon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ably uſed or exerciſed, declared and adjudged for themſelves, their Heirs and Succeſſors, did accept and ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>prove, and all and ſingular to the aforeſaid Mayor and Commonalty and Citizens of the City of <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don</hi> and their Succeſſors, by their ſaid Letters Patents have ratified and confirmed, as by thoſe ſaid Letters Patents (among other things) it doth and may appear. And that our Lord the King that now is, by his Letters Patents, under his Great Seal of <hi>England,</hi> bearing date at <hi>Weſt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>minſter,</hi> the Twenty fourth day of <hi>June,</hi> in the Fifteenth Year of his Reign, which the ſaid Mayor and Commonalty and Citizens of the City of <hi>London</hi> brings here in Court for the ſaid King himſelf, his Heirs and Succeſſors, did ratifie and con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>firm to the Mayor and Commonal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty and Citizens of the City of <hi>London,</hi> their Succeſſors, all and ſin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gular the Juriſdictions, Authorities, Priviledges, Liberties, Franchizes, Freedoms, Immunities, and Cu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtoms whatſoever, which the ſaid Mayor and Commonalty and Citi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>zens of the City of <hi>London</hi> or their Predeceſſors by the Name of Mayor and Commonalty and Citizens of the City of <hi>London,</hi> or by the Name of Mayor, Aldermen, Ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tizens and Commonalty of <hi>London,</hi> or by the Name of Mayor and Ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tizens of the City of <hi>London,</hi> or by the Name of Mayor and Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>monalty of the City of <hi>London,</hi>
                  <pb n="12" facs="tcp:95897:8"/>or by the Name of the Citizens of the City of <hi>London;</hi> or by the Name of the Barons of <hi>London,</hi> or by the Name of the Barons of the City of <hi>London,</hi> or by any other Name what<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſoever, by reaſon or force of the Letters Patents Charters or Confir<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mations in the ſaid Letters Patents of our ſaid now Lord the King be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore mention'd, or of any or any uſe or uſes, preſcription or preſcriptions, or in any other Legal way whatſo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ever in any time or times before then, have been had, or reaſonably have been uſed or exerciſed to have, hold, enjoy and exerciſe all and ſin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gular the ſaid Premiſes to the Mayor and Commonalty and Citizens of the City of <hi>London</hi> aforeſaid, and their Succeſſors for ever, ſo fully, freely, and wholly as in as ample manner and form as by the ſaid Let<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ters Patents above mentioned, to be given or granted, or any other uſe, preſcription, or any other Legal man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner or Right whatſoever before then reſpectively have been had, obtain'd or enjoy'd as if ſeparately, ſingly and name by name in, and by the ſaid Letters Patents of our ſaid King that now is, were, or have been expreſſed, nominated, declared, granted and manifeſted, as by the ſaid Letters Patents among other things more fully it doth, and may appear; And by that Authority, the ſaid Major and Commonalty and Citizens of the City of <hi>London</hi> by the time in the Information aforeſaid above ſpe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cified have been uſed and hitherto do uſe and claim to have, and uſe the Liberties, Priviledges, and Franchi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>zes to be of themſelves one Body Corporate and Politick in Matter, Deed, and Name, by the Name of May or and Commonalty and Citi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>zens of the City of <hi>London,</hi> and by that Name to Plead, and be Implead<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed; to Anſwer, and be Anſwered; as to them it hath or may be Law<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful.
<pb n="13" facs="tcp:95897:8"/>Without that that the ſaid Mayor and Commonalty and Citi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>zens of the City of <hi>London</hi> of theſe Liberties, Priviledges, and Franchi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>zes upon our now Soveraign Lord the King by the time aforeſaid in the Information above ſpecified have been Uſurped, or do Uſurp as by that Information for our ſaid Lord the King above it is ſuppoſed. Which all and ſingular the ſaid Mayor and Commonalty and Ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tizens of the City of <hi>London</hi> are rea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dy to verifie, from whence they pray Judgment; And that the Liber<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties, Priviledges and Franchizes to them and their Succeſſors for ever, ſhould be allowed and adjudged, and that they may be diſmiſſed, as alſo the Premiſes from this Court, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> And the ſaid Mayor and Commo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nalty and Citizens of the City of <hi>London,</hi> ſo as their Liberties, Privi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ledges, and Franchizes following, <hi>viz.</hi> Them to have Sheriffs of the City and County of the City of <hi>London,</hi> and Sheriff of the County of <hi>Middleſex,</hi> and to Name, and Elect of themſelves their Perſons to be Sheriffs of the City aforeſaid and County of the ſaid City, and She<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riff of <hi>Middleſex,</hi> and thoſe ſo Na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>med and Elected to be made and conſtituted Sheriffs of the ſaid City and County of the ſaid City, and Sheriff of the ſaid County of <hi>Mid<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dleſex,</hi> and as Sheriff of the ſaid City &amp; in the County of the ſaid City to execut &amp; Retorne all Writs, Bills, and Precepts of our ſaid Lord the King for the Adminiſtration and Execu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion of Juſtice within the ſaid City, and County of the ſaid City, to per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>form and do what ſhall appertain or belong to the Office of Sheriff, and alſo to do and perform, and all and ſingular others within the ſaid Ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty and County of the ſame, which ſhall appertain to, or belong to the Office of Sheriff, alſo to ſerve as
<pb n="14" facs="tcp:95897:9"/>Sheriff for the County of <hi>Middle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſex,</hi> and all Writs, Bills and Pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cepts of our Lord the King with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in the ſaid County of <hi>Middleſex,</hi> for the Adminiſtration and Execu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion of Juſtice there, to perform and make return thereof, which be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>longs or appertains to the Office of Sheriff: Say our ſaid Lord the King ought not to impeach or hin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der them the Mayor, Commonal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty and Citizens of the City of <hi>London</hi> by occaſion thereof, becauſe they ſay, that the City of <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don</hi> is and time out of mind hath been an ancient City and County of themſelves. And that the ſaid County of <hi>Middleſex,</hi> by the time aforeſaid, hath been and is an an<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cient County. And that the Ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tizens of the ſaid City are and from which time, beyond the me<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mory of Man, hath been one Body Corporate and Politick, not only by the Name of Mayor and Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>monalty of the Citizens of the City of <hi>London,</hi> but alſo by the Names of the Citizens of <hi>London.</hi> And that King <hi>John</hi> ſome time King of <hi>England,</hi> by his Letters Patents under his Great Seal of <hi>England,</hi> bearing date at his good Town upon <hi>Tokam,</hi> the fifth day of <hi>July,</hi> in the Firſt Year of his Reign, which the ſaid Mayor and Commonal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty and Citizens of the City of <hi>London</hi> brings here in Court, did grant to the Citizens of <hi>London</hi> aforeſaid, Sheriffs of <hi>London</hi> and <hi>Middleſex,</hi> with all things and Cuſtoms which did appertain and belong to the ſaid Sheriffs within the City and without, by Land and by Water, to have and to hold to them for Ever. And beſides, that the ſaid King <hi>John,</hi> by his ſaid Letters Patents, did grant to the ſaid Ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tizens of <hi>London,</hi> that they of them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelves ſhould make Sheriffs whom<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſoever they would, and amove them
<pb n="15" facs="tcp:95897:9"/>when they pleaſed, as by the ſaid Letters Patents (among other things) more fully appears. And that in the Great Charter of the Liberties of <hi>England,</hi> in the Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment of our Lord <hi>Henry</hi> the Third ſometime King of <hi>England,</hi> at <hi>Weſtminſter,</hi> in the County of <hi>Middleſex,</hi> in the Ninth Year of his Reign, held, made, and provi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ded, it is contained that the City of <hi>London</hi> ſhould have all their an<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cient Liberties and Cuſtoms. And the ſaid Mayor, Commonalty and Citizens of the City of <hi>London</hi> further ſay, that the ſaid King <hi>Hen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry</hi> the Third, by his Letters Patents under his Great Seal of <hi>England,</hi> bearing date at <hi>Weſtminſter</hi> afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, the Eighteenth day of <hi>Februa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry,</hi> in the Eleventh Year of his Reign, which the ſaid Mayor and Commonalty and Citizens of the City of <hi>London</hi> brings here in Court, did confirm to the Citizens of <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don,</hi> Sheriffs of <hi>London</hi> and <hi>Middle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſex,</hi> with all things and Cuſtoms that did belong to the ſaid She<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riffs within the City, and without, by Land and by Water, as by the ſaid Letters Patents (among other things) more fully appears. And that King <hi>Edward</hi> the Third in his Parliament at <hi>Weſtminſter,</hi> held in the County of <hi>Middleſex,</hi> in the Firſt Year of his Reign, by his Charter, with the aſſent of the Prelates, Earls, Barons, and the whole Commonalty of this Realm, in his ſaid Parliament at <hi>Weſtmin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſter</hi> being aſſembled, and by Au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thority of the ſaid Parliament, did then confirm to the Citizens of the City of <hi>London</hi> the ſaid Liberties following (among other things) to have to themſelves and Succeſſors for Ever. Firſt in reciting, that whereas in the Great Charter of the Liberties of <hi>England</hi> it is con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tained, that the City of <hi>London</hi>
                  <pb n="16" facs="tcp:95897:10"/>ſhould have all their ancient Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>berties and Cuſtoms. And that the ſaid Citizens at the time of making the ſaid Charter, and in the times of King <hi>Edward</hi> the Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feſſor, and <hi>William</hi> the Conque<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ror, and other the Progenitors of the ſaid King <hi>Edward</hi> the Third, divers Liberties and Cuſtoms, not only by the Charters of their Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>genitors, but alſo without Char<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ters of ancient Cuſtoms have had, the ſaid King <hi>Edward</hi> the Third did will and grant for himſelf and his Heirs, by the authority of thoſe Charters, that the ſaid Citizens ſhould have their Liberties accord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing to the Form of the Great Char<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter above-mentioned. And that for any Perſonal Offence, or Perſonal Judgment of any Officer of the ſaid City, their Liberties ſhould not be taken into the hands of the ſaid King <hi>Edward</hi> the Third or his Heirs, but of ſuch Officer the like Offence ſhould be required of, and puniſh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, as by the ſaid Charters, bearing date at <hi>Weſtminſter</hi> aforeſaid, the Sixth day of <hi>March,</hi> in the Firſt Year of the Reign of the ſaid King <hi>Edward</hi> the Third, under his Great Seal of <hi>England,</hi> here brought into Court (among other things) more fully may appear. And the ſaid Mayor, Commonalty and Citizens of the City of <hi>London</hi> further ſay, that at the inſtance and requeſt of the Commons of <hi>England,</hi> in the Parliament of King <hi>Richard</hi> the Se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cond, after the Conqueſt, at <hi>Weſt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>minſter</hi> aforeſaid, in the Seventh Year of his Reign, held and aſſem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bled for the greater quiet and peace of his Subjects, to maintain and for the publick good, all Cuſtoms, Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>berties, Priviledges and Franchiſes of the ſaid City then to the Citizens of that City and their Succeſſors, although they have not been uſed or abuſed, was ratified and confirmed
<pb n="17" facs="tcp:95897:10"/>by the Authority of the ſaid Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment. And that the late King <hi>Henry</hi> the Sixth, by His Letters Patents under his Great Seal of <hi>Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land,</hi> bearing Date at <hi>Weſtminſter</hi> aforeſaid the 26th. day of <hi>October</hi> in the 23<hi>d.</hi> Year of his Reign which the ſaid Mayor and Commonalty and Citizens of the City of <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don</hi> brings here in Court for them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelves, their Heirs and Succeſſors did confirm to the Mayor and Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>monalty, and to the Citizens of the City of <hi>London,</hi> and their Succeſſors all and ſingular their Liberties, Fran<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chizes and Free Cuſtoms ſo intire and unmoleſted, like as in any time of the Progenitors of the ſaid King <hi>Henry</hi> the Sixth, they evermore quietly and freely have had, and held, as by the ſaid Letters Patents among other things more fully may appear. And that King <hi>Edward</hi> the 4th. by his Letters Patents under his Great Seal of <hi>England</hi> bearing date at <hi>Weſtminſter</hi> aforeſaid the Ninth day of <hi>November,</hi> in the Second Year of his Reign which the Major and Commonalty and Citizens of the City of <hi>London</hi> brings here in Court for themſelves, and their Heirs did confirm to the Mayor and Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>monalty and Citizens of the City of <hi>London</hi> and their Succeſſors for Ever, all and ſingular their Liber<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties, Franchizes and Free Cuſtoms ſo intire and untouched like as in any time of the Progenitors of the ſaid King <hi>Edward</hi> the 4th. more quietly and freely they ever had and held. And further, the ſaid King <hi>Edward</hi> the Fourth, by his Letters Patents did grant to the Mayor and Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>monalty and Citizens of <hi>London,</hi> that although they, or their Prede<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſſors, or Mayor and Aldermen of the City aforeſaid, or their Prede<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſſors before that, or their Suc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſſors from thence after any, or to any Liberties, Freedoms, Conceſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons,
<pb facs="tcp:95897:11"/>Ordinances of Articles, or Free Cuſtoms, or of any other in the ſaid Letters Patents of the ſaid King <hi>Ed<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ward</hi> the Fourth, or any other his Letters Patents, of his Progenitors Kings of <hi>England,</hi> to the ſaid Mayor and Commonalty granted, contain'd in any Caſe ariſing, that have not been fully uſed or abuſed, the ſaid King <hi>Edward</hi> the Fourth is unwil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling that the Mayor and Commo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nalty Aldermen and Citizens or their Succeſſors ſhall incur the for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feiture of any the Premiſes, but that they and their Succeſſors to all and ſingular the Liberties, Free<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>doms, Grants, Ordinances, Articles, Free Cuſtoms, and whatſoever elſe in the ſaid Charters and Letters con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tained the like not uſed or abuſed, and any of them from thence, ful<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly and freely ſhall uſe and enjoy without the Impeachment or Im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pediment of the ſaid King, or his Heirs, Juſtices, Eſcheators, Sheriffs, or any Bayliff or Officer of the ſaid King, or of any other whatſoever, as by the ſaid Letters Patents of the ſaid King <hi>Edward</hi> the 4th. brought here in Court among other things more fully may appear. And that the late King <hi>Henry</hi> the 7th. by his Letters Patents under his Great Seal of <hi>England</hi> bearing Date at <hi>Weſt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>minſter</hi> aforeſaid, the 23d. Day of <hi>July</hi> in the Twentieth Year of his Reign, which the ſaid Mayor and Commonalty and Citizens of the City of <hi>London</hi> brings here in Court for themſelves, and their Succeſſors did Ratifie and Confirm to the Mayor and Commonalty and Citi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>zens of the City of <hi>London</hi> and their Succeſſors, all and ſingular the Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>berties, Priviledges, Freedoms, and Free Cuſtoms, to which they the Mayor Commonalty and Citizens or their Succeſſors have been ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cuſtomed to have, exerciſe, or enjoy, or have, or ought to have been
<pb n="18" facs="tcp:95897:11"/>uſed, and fully, plainly and wholly, as if all and ſingular the ſeveral words in the ſaid Letters Patents were expreſſed, declared and mani<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feſted, as by the ſaid Letters Patents (among other things) more fully may appear. And that the late King <hi>Henry</hi> the Eighth by his Let<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ters Patents, under his Great Seal of <hi>England,</hi> bearing date at <hi>Weſt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>minſter</hi> aforeſaid, the Twelfth day of <hi>July</hi> in the Fifth Year of his Reign, which the Mayor and Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>monalty and Citizens of the City of <hi>London</hi> brings here in Court all Grants and others whatſoever in the ſaid Letters Patents of the ſaid King <hi>John</hi> above ſpecified and contain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, that he the ſaid King <hi>Henry</hi> the Eighth and his Succeſſors, to the Mayor and Commonalty and Citi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>zens of the City of <hi>London</hi> and their Succeſſors, did ratifie and confirm, as by the ſaid Letters Patents of the ſaid King <hi>Henry</hi> the Eighth (among other things) more fully appears. And that the ſaid late King <hi>Edward</hi> the Sixth, by his Let<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ters Patents, under the Great Seal of <hi>England,</hi> bearing date at <hi>Weſt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>minſter</hi> aforeſaid, the Twenty firſt day of <hi>February,</hi> in the Second Year of his Reign, which the ſaid Mayor and Commonalty and Ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tizens of the City of <hi>London</hi> brings here in Court all Grants and others whatſoever in the ſaid Letters Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tents of the ſaid King <hi>John</hi> above<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mentioned, contained for himſelf and his Heirs, to the Mayor and Commonalty and Citizens of the City of <hi>London</hi> and their Succeſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſors, did ratifie and confirm, as by the ſaid Letters Patents of the ſaid King <hi>Edward</hi> the Sixth (among other things) more fully appears. And that the late Queen <hi>Mary</hi> by her Letters Patents, under the great
<pb facs="tcp:95897:12"/>Seal of <hi>England,</hi> bearing date at <hi>Weſtminſter</hi> aforeſaid, the firſt day of <hi>March,</hi> in the firſt Year of her Reign, which the ſaid Mayor and Commonalty and Citizens of the City of <hi>London</hi> brings here in Court, for her ſelf, her Heirs and Succeſſors, all Grants and others whatſoever in the ſaid Letters Patents of the ſaid King <hi>John</hi> above ſpecified, contained to the Mayor and Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>monalty and to the Citizens of the City of <hi>London</hi> aforeſaid and their Succeſſors, did ratifie and confirm, as by the ſaid Letters Patents more fully appears. And that the late Queen <hi>Elizabeth,</hi> by her Letters Patents, under her Great Seal of <hi>England,</hi> bearing date at <hi>Weſtmin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſter</hi> aforeſaid, the Ninth day of <hi>May,</hi> in the Fourth Year of her Reign, which the ſaid Mayor and Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>monalty and Citizens of the City of <hi>London</hi> brings here in Court, for her ſelf, her Heirs and Succeſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſors, all Grants and others whatſoe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver in the ſaid Letters Patents of the ſaid King <hi>John</hi> above ſpecified and contained, to the Mayor and Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>monalty and Citizens of the City of <hi>London</hi> and their Succeſſors, did ratifie and confirm, as by the ſaid Queen <hi>Elizabeth</hi>'s Letters Patents (among other things) more fully appears. And the ſaid Mayor and Commonalty and Citizens of the City of <hi>London</hi> further ſay, that King <hi>James,</hi> by his Letters Patents, under his Great Seal of <hi>England,</hi> bearing date at his Honour of <hi>Hampton-Court,</hi> the Twenty fourth day of <hi>September,</hi> in the Sixth Year of his Reign, which the ſaid Mayor and Commonalty and Citizens of the City of <hi>London</hi> brings here in Court by reciting, That where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>as the moſt part of the Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>genitors of the late King,
<pb n="19" facs="tcp:95897:12"/>ſometimes Kings of <hi>England</hi> of their ſpecial Grace, and for the ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny grateful laudable and continued Services, by the Mayor Commonal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty and Cityzens of the City of <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don,</hi> and their Predeceſſors in times paſt, done and unre warded, alſo for divers others urgent Cauſes and Conſiderations, them ſeveral<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly moving, did give grace, and confirm to the Mayor and Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>monalty and Cityzens or of the City of <hi>London</hi> and their Succeſſors diverſe Libertys Privileges, Franchiſes, Im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>munities, Authorityes, Iuriſdictions, Ordinances, Cuſtoms, and Freedoms, as by the ſeveral Letters, Patents of the ſaid Progenitors and Predeceſſors Kings of <hi>England</hi> more fully and manifeſt, it doth and may appear the ſaid King <hi>James</hi> for, and in conſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>deration of the moſt faithful, and conſtant, and laudable ſervice by the Mayor and Commonalty and Cityzens of the City of <hi>London</hi> a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid to him in his firſt coming to this Realm, and ſtill continued then manifeſted and moſt faithful<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly done and unrewarded all and ſingular Letters, Patents, Charters, and confirmations of his moſt no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble Progenitors and Anteceſſors to to the Mayor and Commonalty and to the Cityzens of the City of <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don</hi> and their Predeceſſors, by whatſoever named, Incorporated before that time made granted or confirmed and all and ſingular Do<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nations, Grants, Confirmations, Reſtitutions, Cuſtoms, Ordinances. Explanations, Articles, and all other things whatſoever, in whatſoever Letters, Patents, or Charters what<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſoever of his Progenitors, Predeceſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſors, or Anteceſſors Kings of <hi>Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land.</hi> And alſo all and ſingular in the ſaid Letters, Patents, Charters Grants, Confirmations, or any of them contained, recited, ſpecified, confirmed or explained, and all and ſingular Juriſdictions, Authorities, Priviledges, Liberties, and Fran<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chiſes, Freedoms, Immunities, free
<pb facs="tcp:95897:13"/>Cuſtoms and Hereditaments what<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſoever, which the ſaid Mayor and Commonalty and Cityzens of the City of <hi>London</hi> aforeſaid or their Predeceſſors by the name of Mayor and Comminalty and Citizens of the City of <hi>London,</hi> or by the name of Mayor and Al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dermen of the City of <hi>London,</hi> or by the Name of Mayor Cityzens and Commonalty of the City of <hi>London,</hi> or by the name of Mayor and Cityzens of the City of <hi>London,</hi> or by the name of Citizens of the City of <hi>London,</hi> Or by the name of Barons of <hi>London,</hi> or by the name Barons of the City of <hi>London,</hi> or by any other name whatſoever by rea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon or force of any Letters, Patents, Charters or Confirmation of any the Progenitors, Predeceſſors, An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeceſſors of the ſaid King <hi>James</hi> in any time or times have had or rea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſonably have been uſed or exerciſed hath ratified and confirmed and for himſelf his Heirs and Succeſſors did accept and approve and all and ſingular to the ſaid Mayor and Commonalty and to the Cityzens of the City of <hi>London</hi> and their Suc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſſors by the ſaid Letters, Patents, did ratifie and confirm to have, hold, enjoy and exerciſe all and ſin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gular the ſaid premiſſes to the ſaid Mayor and Commonalty and to the Cityzens of the City of <hi>London</hi> afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid and to their Succeſſors for Ever, ſo fully, clearly, and wholy in as ample manner and forme as if ſeper<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ately ſingly, and name by name thoſe ſaid Letters Patents were ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>preſſed, named, declared, recited and manifeſted, as by the ſaid Let<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ters, Patents among other things more fully appear. And that our late Soveraign Ld. King <hi>Charles</hi> the firſt by his Letters, Patents under his Great Seale of <hi>England</hi> bearing date at <hi>Weſt.</hi> the 18th. day of <hi>October</hi> in the 14th. year of his Reign, which the ſaid Mayor and Commonalty
<pb n="20" facs="tcp:95897:13"/>and Cityzens of the City of <hi>London</hi> brings here in Courts all and ſingu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lar Priviledges, Liberties, Franchiſes, Freedoms, Immunities and free-Cuſtoms whatſoever, which the ſaid Mayor and Commonalty and Cityzens of the City of <hi>London</hi> or their Predeceſſors by the name of the Mayor and Commonalty and Cityzens of the City of <hi>London,</hi> Or by the name of Mayor and Alder<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men, Cityzens and Commonalty of <hi>London,</hi> Or by the name of May<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>or and Cittizens of the City of <hi>London,</hi> or by the name of Mayor and Commonalty of <hi>London,</hi> Or by the name of the Cityzens of the City <hi>London,</hi> or by the name of Barons of <hi>London,</hi> or by the name of Ba<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rons of the City of <hi>London,</hi> or by any other name whatſoever by reaſon or force of the ſaid Letters, Patents, of the ſaid King <hi>John</hi> or of any other Letters, Patents, Charters, or Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>firmations in the ſaid Letters, Patent, of the ſaid late King <hi>Charles</hi> the firſt mentioned or in uſe or by pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſcription or by any other lawful manner in any time or times before that they have had or reaſonablely have uſed or exerciſed hath adjudged and conformed the ſame for himſelf his Heirs and Succeſſors, and accept<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed and approved them, all and ſin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gular to the ſaid Mayor and Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>monalty and Cityzens of the City of <hi>London</hi> and their Succeſſors by his ſaid Letters, Patents hath rati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fied and confirmed as by the ſaid Letters, Patents among other things more fully appears, And that our now ſaid Soveraign Lord the King by his Letters, Patents under his Great Seale of <hi>England</hi> bearing date at <hi>Weſtm.</hi> the 24th. day of <hi>June</hi> in the 15th year of his Reign which the ſaid Mayor and Commonalty and Cityzens of the City of <hi>London</hi> brings here in Court, for himſelf his Heris and Succeſſors hath ratified and confirmed to the Mayor and
<pb facs="tcp:95897:14"/>Commonalty and to the Cityzens of the City of <hi>London,</hi> and their Succeſſors all and ſingular the Juriſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dictions, Authorities, Priviledges, Liberties Franchiſes, Feeedoms, Im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>munities, and Cuſtoms whatſoever, which the ſaid Mayor and Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>monalty and Cityzens of the City of <hi>London,</hi> or their Prepeceſſors, by the name of Mayor and Commo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nalty and Cityzens of the City of <hi>London,</hi> or by the name of the May<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>or and Alderman Cityzens and Commonalty of <hi>London,</hi> or by the name of Mayor and Cityzens of the City of <hi>London</hi> or by the name of Mayor and Commonalty of the City of <hi>London,</hi> or by the name of the Cityzens of the City of <hi>London,</hi> or by the name of the Barons of <hi>London,</hi> or by the name of the Ba<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rons of the City of <hi>London,</hi> or by any other name whatſoever by reaſon or force of the ſaid Letters, Patents of the ſaid King <hi>John,</hi> or of any other Letters Patents, Charters, or Confir<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mations in the ſaid Letters, Patents of our now ſaid Soveragin Lord the King before mentioned, or of any or any uſe or uſes Preſcription or Preſcriptions, or in any other law<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful manner whatſoever in any time or times before that, or reaſonably have uſed or exerciſed to have, hold, enjoy, and exerciſe all &amp; ſingular the Premiſes aforeſaid to the ſaid Mayor and Commonalty &amp; to the Citizens of the City of <hi>London</hi> &amp; their Succeſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſors for ever ſo fully, freely, &amp; intire, in as ample manner and form as in the ſaid Letters, Patents above is mentioned to be given or granted, or any other uſe, preſcription, or in any other lawful manner or right whatſoever before that reſpectively had been obtained, or enjoyed as if ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verally ſingly, and name by name in and by the ſaid Letters Patents of his now preſent Majeſty were na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>med, declar'd, granted and manifeſted as by the ſaid Letters Patents a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mong other things morefully appears</p>
               <pb n="21" facs="tcp:95897:14"/>
               <p>And the ſaid Mayor and Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>monalty, and Citizens of the City of <hi>London,</hi> further ſay, That from the time of granting the ſaid Let<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ters Patents of the ſaid King <hi>John,</hi> hitherto, they the ſaid Mayor and Commonalty and Citizens of the City of <hi>London,</hi> have Sheriff of the City and County of the City of <hi>London,</hi> and Sheriff for the County of <hi>Middleſex,</hi> and in every year have named and elected of them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelves two Perſons, Citizens of the City, to be Sheriffs of the ſaid Ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty and County of the ſaid City, and Sheriff for the County of <hi>Mid<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dleſex;</hi> and thoſe ſo named and elected, have conſtituted and made Sheriffs of the ſaid City and Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty of the ſaid City, and Sheriff of the County of <hi>Middleſex;</hi> And as Sheriffs of the ſaid City and Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty of the ſaid City, to execute and return all Writs, Bills, and Precepts of our Sovereign Lord the King, for the Adminiſtration and Execu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion of Juſtice within the ſaid City and County of the ſaid City to be done and performed, which belongs to the Office of Sheriff: And to do and exerciſe all and ſingular other things within the ſaid City and County of the ſaid City, which be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>longs to the Office of Sheriff: And as Sheriff of <hi>Middleſex,</hi> for the ſaid County to ſerve, and all Writs, Bills, and Precepts of our ſaid Sovereign Lord the King, within the ſaid County of <hi>Middleſex,</hi> for the Ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miniſtration and Execution of Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtice, there to exerciſe, and make return thereof, which belongs to the Office of Sheriff. And by that Authority the Mayor and Commo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nalty and Citizens of the City of <hi>London,</hi> during the time in the ſaid Information above-ſpecified, have uſed, and hitherto do uſe and claim to have and uſe the Liberties, Pri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vileges and Franchiſes, to have
<pb n="22" facs="tcp:95897:15"/>Sheriffs of the City and County of the City of <hi>London,</hi> and Sheriffs for the County of <hi>Middleſex,</hi> and to name and chuſe of themſelves two Perſons to be Sheriffs of the ſaid City and County of the ſaid City, and Sheriff of the County of <hi>Middleſex;</hi> and thoſe ſo named and elected, to make and conſtitute Sheriffs of the ſaid City and Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty of the ſaid City, and Sheriff of the County of <hi>Middleſex;</hi> and as Sheriffs of the ſaid City and Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty of the ſaid City, to execute and return all Letters, Bills, and Pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cepts of our ſaid Lord the King, for the Adminiſtration and Execu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion of Juſtice, within the ſaid Ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty and County of the ſaid City to be done and performed, as to the Office of Sheriff belongs; and alſo to do and perform all and ſingular other things within the ſaid City and County of the ſaid City, which belongs to the Office of Sheriff; and as Sheriff of the County of <hi>Middleſex</hi> to ſerve for that County, and all Writs, Bills, and Precepts of our ſaid Lord the King, within the ſaid County of <hi>Middleſex,</hi> for the Adminiſtration and Execution of Juſtice there to be performed, and to make return thereof, which be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>longs to the Office of Sheriff, as to them it ſhall and may be lawful to do.</p>
               <p>Without that, That they the ſaid Mayor and Commonalty and Ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tizens of the City of <hi>London,</hi> of their Liberties, Privileges, and Franchiſes, upon our ſaid Lord the King, for the time in the ſaid Infor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mation ſpecified, have uſurped, and do uſurp, as by the ſaid Imformati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on for our ſaid Sovereign Lord the King it is ſuppoſed, and all and ſingular they the ſaid Mayor and Commonalty and Citizens of the City of <hi>London</hi> are ready to veri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fie; whereof they require Judg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment,
<pb n="23" facs="tcp:95897:15"/>and that their Liberties, Pri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vileges, and Franchiſes, to them and their Succeſſors, henceforth for ever may be allowed and adjudged: and that they may be diſmiſſed, as alſo the Premiſſes, from this Court, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>And they the ſaid Mayor and Commonalty and Citizens of the City of <hi>London,</hi> ſo as the Liberties, Privileges and Franchiſes following, to wit, the Mayor of the ſaid City, and ſuch Aldermen who have exe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cuted the Office of Mayor, and thereof be diſmiſſed, and that three Senior Aldermen of the ſaid City, who have ſtood longeſt in the Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fice of Aldermen thereof, and have not underwent the Burden and Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fice of Mayor of the ſaid City, to be Juſtices of the Peace within the ſaid City, and at the Seſſions of the Peace, and Pleas of the Crown, to wit, ſuch Pleas of the Crown as the Juſtices of our ſaid Lord the King lawfully aſſigned to hold within the ſaid City, and all Felonies, Ri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ots, Routs, and unlawful Conven<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ticles in the ſaid City, to inquire, hear and determine, in the ſaid In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>formation mentioned, ſay, That our ſaid Lord the King them the ſaid Mayor and Commonalty and Citizens of the City of <hi>London,</hi> ought not by occaſion thereof to impeach or hinder, becauſe they ſay the ſaid City of <hi>London</hi> is, and from that time beyond the memo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry of Man hath been an ancient City or ancient County of them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelves, and Citizens of the ſaid City are, and from that time beyond the memory of Man have been one Bo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dy Corporate and Politick, in Mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter, Fact, and Name, by the Name of Mayor and Commonalty and Ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tizens of the City of <hi>London.</hi> And that the ſaid late King <hi>Charles</hi> the Firſt, by His Letters Patents under His Great Seal of <hi>England,</hi> bearing date at <hi>Weſtminſter</hi> the Eighteenth
<pb n="24" facs="tcp:95897:16"/>day of <hi>October,</hi> in the Fourteenth Year of His Reign, which the ſaid Mayor and Commonalty and Citi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>zens of the City of <hi>London</hi> brings here in Court, for Himſelf, His Heirs and Succeſſors, did grant to the Mayor and Commonalty and Citizens of the City of <hi>London,</hi> and their Succeſſors, That the May<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>or and Recorder of the ſaid City for the time being, and the Mayor and Recorder who for the time ſhall be, and not only thoſe Aldermen who have been before Mayors of the City, but alſo thoſe Aldermen who hereafter ſhall bear the Office of Mayor of the ſaid City, altho from the Mayoralty they ſhould depart or be diſmiſſed, but thoſe Aldermen ſhould ſtand, and the three eldeſt Aldermen for the time being, who ſhall be in the Office of Alderman longeſt, and before that time have not executed the Office of Mayor, ſhall be for ever hereafter Juſtices of the Peace, and every of them ſhall be a Juſtice of the Peace for our ſaid Lord the King. His Heirs and Succeſſors, within the ſaid City and Liberties thereof. And the ſaid Mayor, Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>corder, and Aldermen aforeſaid, to all and ſingular the Statutes and Ordinances for the good of the Peace of the King, His Heirs and Succeſſors, and for the Preſervati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on of the ſame, and for the quiet Rule and Government of His Peo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple made and provided, and in all their Articles, not only within the Liberties of the ſame, but alſo with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out the ſaid City, according to the force, form, and effect of the ſame, made to be obſerved, and to all thoſe who according to the form and effect of the ſaid Order and Statutes, or any of them, in the ſaid City and Liberties thereof, ſhall be found Offenders, ſhall be corrected and puniſhed according to the form
<pb n="25" facs="tcp:95897:16"/>of the Ordinance, and of thoſe Ar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ticles to be made: And all thoſe who to any of His Majeſties Sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jects of their Corporation, who ſhall be found out in burning their Houſes by Threatning, ſhall find ſufficient Security for the Peace, or to his Good Behaviour towards our Sovereign Lord the King, and all his People: and if they ſhall refuſe to find ſuch Security, then them to the Goal of <hi>Newgate,</hi> or any other of the King's <hi>Priſons</hi> within the ſaid City of <hi>London,</hi> un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>till ſuch Security ſhall be found, ſhall be kept in ſafe Cuſtody; the Keepers and Juſtices of our Lord the King, and every of them, the Keepers and Juſtices and their Heirs and Succeſſors, within the ſaid City and Liberties, our late Lord King <hi>Charles</hi> the Firſt, for himſelf, his Heirs, and Succeſſors, hath Conſtituted, made, and Or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dained, by His Letters, Patents a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid, and to all ſingular any other to be Executed and Perfor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>med, which the Juſtices and Keep<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ers of the Peace, their Heirs and Succeſſors, within any other Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty of <hi>England</hi> they might Law<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fully exerciſe and perform, and as they ought by vertue of any o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Statute and Ordinance of this Realm, or by vertue of any Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſion of their Heirs, and Succeſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſors, the Peace in any ſuch Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty he is willing to preſerve. Al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſo our ſaid Lord King <hi>Charles</hi> the Firſt, by His ſaid Letters Patents, for Himſelf, His Heirs and Succeſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſors, did grant to the ſaid Mayor and Commonalty, and to the Citi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>zens of the City of <hi>London,</hi> and their Succeſſors, That the Mayor and Recorder of the ſaid City for the time being, and ſuch Aldermen as aforeſaid for the time being, who the Office or Place of Mayor of
<pb n="26" facs="tcp:95897:17"/>that City before that have executed and performed the ſame, and ſuch of the three Eldeſt Aldermen for the time being who the Place of Mayor have not born, or four of them the Mayor, Recorder, and Aldermen, of which the ſaid May<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>or or Recorder for the time being to be one, ſhall be Juſtices of our Lord the King, His Heirs and Suc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſſors, and thoſe Juſtices, their Heirs and Succeſſors, for Himſelf, His Heirs and Succeſſors, hath aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſigned for Ever, to inquire as often and when they ſhall ſee moſt expe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dient, by the Oath of approved and lawful Men, not only of the City aforeſaid, but alſo of the Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>berties of the ſame, by which the very Truth may be the better known of all Murders, Felonies, Sorceries, Inchantments, Whore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom, Magick-Art, Treſpaſſes, Fore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtallers, Regretters, Ingroſſers, and Extortions whatſoever, and all and ſingular other Miſdeeds and Offen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces, of which the ſaid Juſtices of the Peace of our ſaid Lord the King, his Heirs and Succeſſors, may law<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fully be or ought to be inquired, by whomſoever, and what ſort ſoever, within the ſaid City and Liberties thereof, before that time done and perpetrated, or which from thence there ſhall happen to be done and attempted; and not only of all thoſe that ſhall in that City and Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>berties thereof go to Conventicles, againſt the Peace of the late King and His Succeſſors, in the diſtur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bance of His People, His Heirs and Succeſſors, or by force ſhould go or ride Armed, or from thence ſhall preſume to ride or go Armed: And alſo of thoſe which there the Peo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple of our ſaid Lord the King or His Succeſſors ſhall lie in wait to kill, or after ſhall preſume to throw down: Alſo of Hoſtilities,
<pb n="27" facs="tcp:95897:17"/>and all and ſingular Perſons who in abuſe of the Weights and Mea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſures, or in ſelling Victuals con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trary to the form of the Ordi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nance and Statute, or any of them, whereof the Common Advantage of this Realm, and of the People of the late King, His Heirs and Succeſſors, made and provided, ſhall offend, or attempt, in the ſaid City and Liberties thereof, or from thenceforth ſhall preſume to attempt or offend: And al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſo of Sheriffs, Conſtables, Keep<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ers of Gaols, and all other Offi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cers, who in the Execution of their Office about the Premiſſes, or any of them, where they ought not to have them, or hereafter ſhall preſume to have them where he ought not, or carry himſelf remiſs and negli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gent, or from thence ſhall hap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pen to be remiſs or negligent, within the ſaid City and Liber<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties thereof: And of all and ſin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gular the Articles, Circumſtan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces, and others whatſoever, by whomſoever, and of what quali<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty ſoever, in the ſaid City or Liberties thereof, ſhall be done or committed, and which from thenceforth ſhall happen to be done by any whatſoever, in the Premiſſes, or concerning any of them: And to what Indictment ſoever, which before the Mayor or Recorder of the ſaid City for the time being, and ſuch of the ſaid Aldermen, or any four or more of them, whereof the ſaid Mayor or Recorder for the time being ſhall be one, then after<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wards ſhall be taken and inſpe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cted, and Proceſs thereof made, to all and ſingular that are In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dicted, or ſhall happen to be In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dicted, until they ſhall be taken or reſtore themſelves, or ſhall be
<pb n="28" facs="tcp:95897:18"/>or reſtore themſelves, or ſhall be out-lawed, and in making and con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tinuing, and to all and ſingular Murders, Felonies, Sorceries, In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chantments, Whoredom, Magick-Art, alſo falſe Conſpiracies, and o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Miſdeeds, Foreſtallers, Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gretters, Ingroſſers, Extortioners, Conventicles, Indictments, afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid; and all and ſingular other the Premiſſes, according to the Laws and Statutes of this Realm of <hi>England,</hi> as in ſuch like Caſes have uſed to be done or ought to hear and determine: And the Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fenders, and ſuch of them, for their Duties by Fines, Redemptions, Amercements, Forfeitures, and o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther manner according to the Laws and Cuſtoms of this Realm, and Form of the Ordinances and Sta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tutes of the ſame have been ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cuſtomed to be done, or ought to be corrected and puniſhed, and all and ſingular others to do, per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>form, hear, determine, and execute within the ſaid City and Liberties thereof, which Juſtices of the Peace by the Laws and Statutes of this Realm, to do, exerciſe, and inquire, or may be Executed and of Force, and in as ample manner and Form, for any one, or to any one Juſtice of the Peace in any o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther County of this Realm, law<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fully to do, exerciſe, inquire, puniſh, or in any other manner may be exerciſed or of Force, as by the ſaid Letters Patents, among other things, more fully appears. And that our ſaid Lord the King that now is, by his Letters Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tents under the Great Seal of <hi>England,</hi> bearing Date at <hi>Weſt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>minſter</hi> aforeſaid, the 24th. Day of <hi>June,</hi> in the Fifteenth Year of his Reign, which the Mayor and Commonality and Citizens of the City of <hi>London</hi> here brings
<pb facs="tcp:95897:18"/>in Court all Grants and other, whatſoever in the ſaid Letters Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tent of King <hi>Charles</hi> the Firſt above ſpecified, for the ſaid King His Heirs and Succeſſors, to the Mayor and Commonalty, and to the Citi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>zens of the City of <hi>London,</hi> and their Succeſſors for ever, did rati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fie and confirm, as by the ſaid Let<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ters Patents among other things may appear. And they the ſaid Mayor, Commonalty, and Citi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>zens of the City of <hi>London,</hi> fur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther ſay, that in the time of mak<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing the ſaid Letters of the ſaid King <hi>Charles</hi> the Firſt, and whilſt before that, and from that, have hitherto been, and ſtill are Mayor and Recorder of the ſaid City, and Aldermen of the ſaid City, who have not been Mayor, and ſuſtain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed the burden of that Office; and three and more Aldermen of the ſaid City, who have not under<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>went the burden of Mayor there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of: And from that time of the making of the ſaid Letters Patents of the ſaid King <hi>Charles</hi> the Firſt, hitherto the Mayor and Recorder of the ſaid City for the time be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, and ſuch Aldermen for the time being as have not been May<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>or of the ſaid City, alſo three of the Eldeſt Aldermen for the time being, who ſhall be longeſt in that Office of Alderman, and hath not been Mayor of the ſaid City, nor by vertue of the ſaid Letters Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tents, have been Juſtice of the Peace within the ſaid City or Liberties thereof, or by vertue of the ſaid Letters Patents, and according to the Form and Effect of the ſame, of the time, in the time, by the whole time, they have holden Seſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſions of the Peace, and Pleas of the Crown, (to wit) ſuch Pleas of the Crown as ſuch Juſtices of our ſaid Lord the King Aſſigned
<pb n="30" facs="tcp:95897:19"/>to keep by the ſame time lawfully have held or may hold within the ſaid City.</p>
               <p>And by that Authority the ſaid Mayor and Commonalty and Ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tizens of the City of <hi>London</hi> by the time in the Information above<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpecified, have been uſed or hither<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to uſe and claim to have and uſe the Liberties, Privileges, and Fran<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chiſes that the ſaid Mayor of the ſaid City, and ſuch of the Alder<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men of the ſaid City who have not been Mayor therrof, or have been diſmiſſed, or three eldeſt Aldermen of the ſaid City, who have been longeſt Aldermen thereof, or exe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cuted the Office of Mayor, have been Juſtices of the Peace of our ſaid Lord the King, to preſerve the Peace within the ſaid City, and to the Seſſions of the Peace, and Pleas of the Crown, to wit, ſuch Pleas of the Crown as Juſtices of our ſaid Lord the King lawfully aſſigned may hold within the ſaid City, and to all Felonies, Riots, Routs, and unlawful Conventicles within the ſaid City, to inquire, to hear and determine, as to them may ſeem lawful, or be lawful.</p>
               <p>Without that, the ſaid Mayor and Commonalty and Citizens of the City of <hi>London,</hi> of their Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>berties, Privileges, and Franchiſes, upon our ſaid Sovereign Lord the King that now is, by the time in the Information above-ſpecified, have uſurped, or do uſurp, as by the Information for our Lord the King above mentioned it is ſuppo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſed, which all and ſingular the ſaid Mayor and Commonalty and Citi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>zens of the City of <hi>London</hi> are rea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dy to verifie; whereof they pray Judgment, and that their Liberties, Privileges, and Franchiſes, to them and their Heirs, for ever hereafter, may be allowed and adjudged: and
<pb n="31" facs="tcp:95897:19"/>that they, as alſo the Premiſies, may be diſmiſſed from this Court, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>And as to the reſidue of the Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>berties, Privileges, and Franchiſes in the ſaid Information ſpecified, by them the Mayor and Commo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nalty and Citizens of the ſaid City of <hi>London</hi> above-ſpecified not claim<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, they the ſaid Mayor and Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>monalty and Citizens of the City of <hi>London</hi> thoſe Liberties, Privile<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ges and Franchiſes were never uſed, or do uſe, but the ſame do uterly diſclaim.</p>
            </div>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="errata">
            <p>The Courteous Reader is deſired to pardon the ſmall Faults of the Preſs.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
